<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<concerts>
	<Concert country="N" id="1" description="How many Norwegians remember the exact year when the bubonic plague came to their country? 1349 do. They named their band name after this annus horribilis.   The Norwegians play some of the most intense black metal you will ever experience. Often fear-inducingly fast and packed with slaughtering riffs, at times atmospherically lingering and glancing towards the dormant forests.   1349 is created in the ashes of legendary Alvheim, and Satyricon's Frost whips the drums until you might expect blood to spurt out from them.   The most supreme forces from black Norway perform in full corpse paint and with darkness on the agenda.  Released on: Indie Recordings / Target Distribution" web="http://www.legion1349.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/1349/" duration="0" title="Black metal super group from the homeland of the genre." scene="" ros_id="0" artist="1349" artist_initial="1" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.238Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/1349/id79664050?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="2" description="The Danish music export these days is mainly based on a generation of young, healthy men, all of which are filled with complex ideas of pop and a refreshing ability to transform them to critically acclaimed releases. Playing slightly intricate art pop, 4 Guys From The Future are no exception, and these four fellows just might follow in the footsteps of other successes such as Oh No Ono and Treefight For Sunlight. Released on: Tambourhinoceros / Playground" web="http://tambourhinoceros.net/4gftf/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/4-guys-from-the-future/" duration="0" title="Intricate art-pop with a look into the future." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="1" artist="4 guys from the future" artist_initial="4" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.341Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/4-guys-from-the-future/id390942833?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK/GAM" id="3" description="Robert Plant's guitarist Justin Adams and Gambian musician Juldeh Camara conjure up a blend of West African sounds and guitar rock from the cloudy North-West Europe.   On the album Trance Sessions you get an insight into the psychedelic session awaiting Roskilde Festival's audience. Adams' guitars create a lengthy and churning trance atmosphere as part of an exciting symbiosis with Camara's riti, a West African, one-stringed predecessor to the violin. &amp;nbsp; A psychedelic cultural meeting full of both vibrant guitar and ancient African magic.  Released on: Real World / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/justinadamsproducer" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/justin-adams-and-juldeh-camara/" duration="0" title="Trance-rocking meeting between England and West Africa." scene="" ros_id="2" artist="Justin adams and juldeh camara" artist_initial="J" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.341Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/justin-adams-juldeh-camara/id288368198?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="S" id="4" description="In Sweden, Daniel Adams-Ray is on everyone's lips as the new blue’n’yellow pop sensation.  First, Daniel Adams-Ray – or Big Danne as he is called – became popular as one half of the hip hop duo Snook. The duo since went their separate ways. The rapper Daniel then went into a phone booth – and out came the pop singer Daniel.  The debut album, released last autumn, is called Svart vitt och allt däremellan and offers irresistible Motown-inspired pop music sung in a melodious Swedish tongue. Singles such as &quot;Dum av dig&quot; and &quot;Gubben i lådan&quot; has already topped the Swedish charts, and it is as if all of Scandinavia is open to Daniel Adams-Ray.  So it is only natural that the largest Scandinavian festival welcomes the Swede with the hot hit catalogue.  Released on: Lagom / Universal" web="http://www.danieladamsray.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/daniel-adams-ray/" duration="0" title="Swedish-language pop with hints of Motown and disco." scene="" ros_id="3" artist="Daniel adams-ray" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.341Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/daniel-adams-ray/id436564232?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="INT" id="5" description="West Africa meets Cuba with Afrocubism.  This transatlantic supergroup was on the drawing board for the first time in 1996. Back then the Africans did not reach Cuba. Instead, the Cubans recorded Buena Vista Social Club, one of the biggest sales successes of the global music scene.  Now the meeting has taken place and the original vision is finally played out. African superstars such as Toumani Diabaté, Djelimady Tounkara and Bassekou Kouyate are unusual partners for Buena Vista member Eliades Ochoa, often regarded as the Cuban answer to Johnny Cash.  Superb virtuosos like these in bubbly interaction is a unique music event – and a reunion of two cultures that have historically close ties.  Released on: World Circuit/Playground" web="http://www.myspace.com/afrocubism" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/afrocubism/" duration="0" title="Musical meeting between West Africa and Cuba." scene="" ros_id="4" artist="Afrocubism" artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.342Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="african" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/afrocubism/id388445348?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="ISL" id="6" description="Everything from symphonic to mathematical, complex rock finds it way through the amplifiers in Agent Fresco’s successful balancing act between a progressive tour de force and melodic catchiness.  The band combines that distinctive Icelandic sense of fairytales with an epic width that with some righteousness could make them Iceland’s first stadium band.  Hard-hitting rock on volcanos.  Released on: Record Records / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/agentfresco" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/agent-fresco/" duration="0" title="Epic volcano rock with a metallic edge and finesse. " scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="5" artist="Agent fresco" artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.342Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/agent-fresco/id430916967?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="7" description="Alcoholic Faith Mission sounds like an army of hopeless romantics with drum machines and acoustic guitars as their weapons – guarded and timid in the familiar indie fashion. At the same time their melancholy is so heavy that it will make the most heartbreaking teenage love letter sound like a Get well soon greeting card.  Alcoholic Faith Mission is about to release a new record this fall and the little taste from winter’s mini album reveals a band that by all fairness should become the next big Danish indie export.  Released on: PonyRec" web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/alcoholic-faith-mission/" duration="0" title="Hopeless romantics on the verge of a breakthrough." scene="" ros_id="6" artist="Alcoholic faith mission " artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.342Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="FR" id="8" description="French trio Api Uiz have existed since 1995 and plays an experimental and instrumental type of neo-grunge and post-rock at full speed the volume turned to 11.  The band has found inspiration in grunge and noise rock, but most of all Api Uiz has a unique sound. It is loud, noisy, twisted and, above all, uncompromising and energetic.  An original and challenging take on how grunge sounds in 2011.  The act plays as part of the The Ex curation on the Pavilion stage." web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/api-uiz/" duration="0" title="Hypnotic speed-grunge." scene="" ros_id="7" artist="Api uiz" artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.343Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="9" description="Few bands manage like Arctic Monkeys to write universal, British rock full of everyday realism, poetry and cheeky charm.   Their rate is rising steadily on the international rock stock market, and with a new album out in early June, the young Brits are one of the Roskilde audience's biggest requests.   Arctic Monkeys' third visit at Roskilde Festival looks like a sure success on paper, and if we are not mistaken, these lads will still do their utmost to give the audience the perfect no-nonsense rock experience. This is, by the way, Arctic Monkeys' only Scandinavian festival show this year.  Released on: Domino Records / Playground" web="http://www.arcticmonkeys.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/arctic-monkeys-2/" duration="0" title="British rock for just about everybody." scene="" ros_id="8" artist="Arctic monkeys" artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.344Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/arctic-monkeys/id62820413?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="ISL" id="10" description=" Her songs are like a quilt you can crawl under and have a small break from the stress and deadlines of the world.   Ólöf Arnalds sings mainly in her native Icelandic tongue, but also her English-language songs seem to be from a different world without noisy electronics.   You feel the friction of each chord change on her acoustic guitar, and you listen with rapt attention – even when you do not understand any of the wording.   A session with these quiet serenades should be a must for all fans of unadorned beauty.  Released on: 12 Tónar / import" web="http://olofarnalds.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/oloef-arnalds/" duration="0" title="Acoustic lullabies, mostly in Icelandic." scene="" ros_id="9" artist="Ólöf arnalds " artist_initial="Ó" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.344Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="acoustic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/olof-arnalds/id276050587?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="11" description=" God Loves Ugly, is the title of one of their albums. This is one part of the secret behind Atmosphere's success. They do not mind showing ugly snapshots of themselves and of real life.  Atmosphere combines the backbone of hip hop with jazz, alternative rock and soul music, played on real instruments. Their latest album has visits from both Tom Waits and Tunde Adepimpe (TV On the Radio).   It is, however, rapper Slug's tales of love, self-hatred, poverty and drug problems. All served in a technically superior rap, which is Atmosphere's unmistakable triumph.  &amp;nbsp;Released on: Rhymesayers / VME" web="http://www.myspace.com/atmosphere" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/atmosphere/" duration="0" title="Organic, alternative rap." scene="" ros_id="10" artist="Atmosphere" artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.345Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rap" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/atmosphere/id2556490?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="12" description="The good taste gasps with alarm: Autopsy has announced a new album and plays few, exclusive concerts this summer. Roskilde Festival presents the only concert in Scandinavia.  The legendary band emerged from the bloody trail left by another group of black pioneers, namely Death. The mission was clear from the first day of practice in 1987: to create the most brutal and sickening death metal that the synthesizer-happy decade had ever heard.  Autopsy growls, screams and butchers its way through a chaotic attack of rapid riffs, technical drumming and X-rated lyrics. Darkness, brutality and bad taste await our Scandinavian coasts. " web="http://www.autopsydeathmetal.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/autopsy/" duration="0" title="Legendary, X-rated death metal." scene="" ros_id="11" artist="Autopsy" artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.345Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/autopsy/id427831212?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="13" description=" Brian Shimkovitz was in Ghana as part of his education. Here he collected hundreds of cassette tapes with rare African music from Zimbabwe, Ethiopia and Senegal. &amp;nbsp; He has since put the songs from the tapes on his blog Awesome Tapes from Africa, and lots of music-loving Westerners have become addicted to the updates from the New Yorker's fragrant music library.   The popular blog now packs the tour bus. Fans of African music should not cheat themselves of a handful of rare, hard-to-find treats. " web="http://awesometapesfromafrica.blogspot.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/awesome-tapes-from-africa/" duration="0" title="Brooklyn hipster plays cassette tapes from Africa." scene="" ros_id="12" artist="Awesome tapes from africa" artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.345Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="african" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/truckers-of-husk/id274880969?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="14" description="Since 1980 Bad Religion has released loads of melodic, politically indignant records. The formula is essentially the same: three chords and a simple chorus.  Principal songwriters Greg Graffin and Brett Gurewitz can keep on sprinkling gold dust on this simple formula so that the audience never gets enough. It is obvious at the band's live shows where several generations of punk fans are treated with old and new favourites.  Bad Religion are persevering, politically empathic veterans, and they keep on delivering the goods.  Released on: Epitaph / Cosmos Music Group" web="http://www.badreligion.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/bad-religion-2/" duration="0" title="Reliable punk rock with catchy tunes and political indignation." scene="" ros_id="13" artist="Bad religion" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.345Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="punk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/bad-religion/id150160?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="15" description="Imagine an entire choir of female voices singing to you in a hazy, mythological landscape. That is just about the sound of Julianna Barwick’s atmospheric world that is both beautiful, challenging on the ears and full of non-religious spirituality.  Her voice is the undisputed main instrument of the music. Only rarely does she supplement with a little piano or guitar. By means of loops and pedals, the American singer puts layer upon layer upon layer of abstract vocals until you no longer believe that there is only one woman on stage.  Released on: Asthmatic Kitty / VME" web="http://www.juliannabarwick.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/julianna-barwick/" duration="0" title="Surreal, abstract solo singing." scene="" ros_id="14" artist="Julianna barwick" artist_initial="J" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.346Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="alternate" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/julianna-barwick/id415722074?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="16" description="Up until now they have gone under the cryptic name Just A Number 05272011, but on this very date – 27 May 2011 – the Danish electronic act changed its name to Battlekat.  The trendsetting web zine Pitchfork, among others, has persistently tried to find facts about this mysterious quartet who with their metallic and melancholy avant-garde rock references are defining a new and exciting direction for Scandinavian electro pop.  Released on: Good Tape" web="http://battlekat.eu/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/battlekat/" duration="0" title="Mystical electro pop headed for greatness. " scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="15" artist="Battlekat" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.346Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/battlecat/id14809080?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="17" description=" An avant-garde rock band, a jazz band and a dance-friendly pop band are trying to break out when Battles grab their instruments. Fortunately, there is never one of the aforementioned bands who get the upper hand.   Battles float weightless in a galaxy of musical impressions where common boundaries between easy and difficult music seem to go up in pink smoke.   Tyondai Braxton recently left Battles. The remaining band has invited a number of odd guests on the new album that the trio is looking forward to playing live.   Battles are challenging for the brain and power for your dancing shoes – an optimistic vision of how music could sound the in 2111.  Released on: Warp / VME" web="http://bttls.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/battles-1/" duration="0" title="Festive and colourful experimental rock." scene="" ros_id="16" artist="Battles" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.346Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="alternate" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/battles/id33568718?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="KOR" id="18" description="Korea's ancient culture gets an experimental treatment by Be-Being.   The project is created by six already well-established names from the Korean music scene. Be-Being creates an Eastern potpourri of sounds and impressions. Everything from Buddhist chanting and glockenspiels to traditional stringed instruments are in use when the ensemble heads on a journey toward the heart of enlightenment where Buddha may sit smiling indulgently at us all.   Surprise your ears with something quite strange. Be-Being is quite probably unlike anything you have ever heard before. " web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/be-being/" duration="0" title="Experiments with Korean sound and tradition." scene="" ros_id="17" artist="Be-being " artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.347Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="DE" id="19" description="They are huge in Germany and greater parts of Europe. Scandinavia now also gets the opportunity to become better acquainted with Beatsteaks.  With loans from hardcore, power pop and ska, the five friends from Berlin deliver English-language punk rock sparkling with a big musical scope, melodic flair and lots of humour. And despite the fact that the band has now signed with major label Warner – with a new album in the pipeline – there is not the slightest tinge of sell-out.  The attitude is still DIY like when they started their career back in 1995. Beatsteaks are served raw and contains lots of protein.  Released on: Epitaph / Warner" web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/beatsteaks-1/" duration="0" title="Internationally recognised punk rock from Berlin." scene="" ros_id="18" artist="Beatsteaks" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.347Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="instrumental" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="US" id="20" description="As one half of Outkast, he has put southern hip hop on the musical world map. With Sir Lucious Left Foot… The Son of Chico Dusty, Big Boi shows that he is fully capable of delivering the same swagger, style and variety single-handedly. The solo debut is already considered one of today's key hip hop works.  Big Boi can pimp beats, quirky verses, funk, pop choruses and sultry synths, making it a revelation to Outkast fans who saw Andre 3000 as the duo's most important member.  Antwan Andre Patton puts hip hop at his feet as a true dandy with a diamond in the cane, a soft hat and thinly disguised ambitions for world domination.  Released on: Def Jam / Universal" web="http://bigboi.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/big-boi/" duration="0" title="Southern hip hop from one half of Outkast." scene="" ros_id="19" artist="Big boi" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.347Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="hiphop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/big-boi/id130023951?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="21" description="Detroit has delivered its share of noteworthy hip hoppers, of course with a certain Marshall Mathers as a figurehead. In the rapper/producer category it is just as much deceased J Dilla casting long shadows.  But in Black Milk both the motor city and the hip hop genre have an ideal successor. With Tronic he made a name for himself as an artist with skills enough to fill out the album format. Album of the Year from 2010 blooms and develops in a more orchestrated, funk rock direction.  &amp;quot;My shit is Martin Luther, your shit is Martin Lawrence,&amp;quot; postulates Black Milk. Find out that there is truth in his words as he visits Roskilde backed by both keyboardist/singer AB and drummer Daru Jones.  Released on: Fat Beat / VMA" web="http://blackmilk.biz/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/black-milk/" duration="0" title="Detroit hip hop." scene="" ros_id="20" artist="Black milk" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.348Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="hiphop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/black-milk/id215018491?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="22" description="Dubstep, soul, R&amp;amp;B and abstract electronica are some of the tags that have been put on James Blake's music.  His auto-tune-distorted vocals are lowered in a digital acid bath where genres quickly melt down and turn into bubbles on the sound surface. Organic and electronic are no longer true contradictions with James Blake's generation.  This stylistically consistent debutant delivers a mixture of avant-garde daring, electronic playfulness and a desire to communicate broadly with moving and touching pop songs.  James Blake's talent allows him to do it all.  Released on: Polydor / Universal" web="http://jamesblakemusic.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/james-blake/" duration="0" title="Sad robot soul." scene="" ros_id="21" artist="James blake" artist_initial="J" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.349Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rnb" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/james-blake/id59504818?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="23" description="For most people, drum'n'bass is a fully electronic genre with crackling, icy productions.  Bottled in England have a live drummer who helps turn their gigs into a dirty, brutal and non-stopping affair. The concerts are one long mix, ensuring that your feet will never get any rest.  Bottled in England are filled to the neck with rap, grooves, catchy songs and – as the band name implies – massive inspiration from the UK, urban underground. " web="http://www.bottledinengland.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/bottled-in-england/" duration="0" title="Drum'n'bass with a live drummer." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="22" artist="Bottled in england" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.349Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="US" id="24" description="A lifetime of hard-earned experience is carved in Charles Bradley's soul vocals.   After 40 years with concerts in small clubs, the debut album No Time For Dreaming is finally a reality – delivered by the same people who gave us Sharon Jones &amp;amp; The Dap-Kings. And the limelight has missed someone like him.   Charles Bradley's voice (and hairdo) is reminiscent of James Brown, but the former cook and plumber has a different grim story to tell, which is also heard in the voice.   Always reliable Menahan Street Band delivers a backdrop of brass, organ and groovy rhythms for a party full of funk and soul.  Released on: Daptone Records / VMA" web="http://thecharlesbradley.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/charles-bradley-menahan-street-band/" duration="0" title="Soul-funk full of a lived life and hard-earned experience." scene="" ros_id="23" artist="Charles bradley" artist_initial="C" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.350Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="soul" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/charles-bradley/id206064023?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="25" description="You easily recognise Bright Eyes on the voice whose pain and experience exceeds the years lived. Conor Oberst’s voice enjoys the company of well-written songs that in an instant can go from flickering beautifully and quietly as a candle to bursting out in a sea of flames of emotional rock.  In the course of numerous albums and EPs, the still young songwriter has gone through an impressive development. Reportedly, The People’s Key is the last record under the moniker Bright Eyes.  Conor Oberst has gone from being a breathlessness-struck teenager to a fully mature songwriter with air under his wings, political indignation and a great arsenal of musical effects.&amp;nbsp;  Released on: Polydor / Universal" web="http://www.conoroberst.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/bright-eyes-1/" duration="0" title="Alternative folk-rock in American wide-screen." scene="" ros_id="24" artist="Bright eyes" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.350Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="folk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/bright-eyes/id6547614?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="26" description="The deathcore genre has few representatives that are both so hugely popular and uncompromising in their musical quest as Bring Me the Horizon.  The British band plays surprising deathcore that divides the waters by choosing countless unexpected exits, making the final result sound both violent, original and compellingly epic.  Here are treats for both emo kids and fans of pure metal.  Surrender yourself to the sea of flames when Bring Me the Horizon alternates between brutal power chords with desperately screaming vocals and more melodic, stormy passages.  Released on: Visible Noise / Target Distribution" web="http://www.bringmethehorizon.co.uk/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/bring-me-the-horizon/" duration="0" title="Brutal, varied deathcore." scene="" ros_id="25" artist="Bring me the horizon" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.351Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/bring-me-the-horizon/id121043936?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="27" description="Not many young men can replace Manchester-inspired gloominess with danceable hipster hip hop in just a few years without losing their artistic integrity.  Yet, this is what Asbjørn Auring Grimm has done under the name Brother Grimm. The instrumentation is mostly kept to guitar, bass and drums, but the cheeky cockney rap gives the music an unusual countermeasure with a very un-Danish hip hop sound as a result.  Released on: Mermaid" web="http://www.myspace.com/brothergrimmband" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/brother-grimm/" duration="0" title="Indie rap’s great Danish hope." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="26" artist="Brother grimm" artist_initial="B" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.351Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="indie" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/brother-grimm/id428516481?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="BRA" id="28" description="São Paulo has an adventurous acquaintance: a female artist mastering jazzy and playful pop with a European touch.  Karina Buhr is also of German descent and is widely regarded as one of Brazil's most interesting artists right now. Her 2010 album Eu Menti Pra Você (I have lied to you) has in South American media been proclaimed one of the best albums of the year.  Buhr's catchy pop music draws on samba, jazz and European pop and has, by virtue of its warm organ tones and gentle wind instruments, an immediate but also inscrutable charm.  Released on: Tratore / import" web="http://www.karinabuhr.com.br/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/karina-buhr/" duration="0" title="Sophisticated, inscrutable samba pop." scene="" ros_id="27" artist="Karina buhr" artist_initial="K" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.351Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/karina-buhr/id274713049?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="PRI" id="29" description="They are originally linked to the reggaeton genre, a labeling they have left behind.  Grammy-bombarded Calle 13 – whose nucleus is rapper/vocalist Residente and multitasker Visitante - use a wide palette in their Spanish-language music where hip hop, pop and cumbia are just some of the many genres hijacked by the two brothers in their danceable urban output.  On stage you will find 11 well-playing musicians which is not one man or woman to many when the aim is organic, borderless pop filled to the brim with Latin American flavour and politically indignant hip hop attitude.  Released on: Sony Music Latin / import" web="http://lacalle13.com/intro/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/calle-13/" duration="0" title="Festive and unpredictable Latin hip hop." scene="" ros_id="28" artist="Calle 13" artist_initial="C" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.351Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="hippo" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/calle-13/id101668733?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="30" description="A new woman conquers the rock scene. Her name is Anna Calvi, and she has been hailed as “The biggest thing since Patti Smith” by Brian Eno while Nick Cave in 2010 invited this debutant to be the support act for Grinderman.  And you will soon discover why this powerful singer has caught the attention of these rock veterans. Anna Calvi’s music is like a perfume oozing of erotic and nostalgic elegance. Like a meeting between Edith Piaf and Nina Simone – if they were playing guitars juiced with electricity.  She writes pop songs dripping with passion, performed with a rare, voluminous vocal and with a solid grip on her faithful Telecaster. Look forward to Anna Calvi: a debutant full of life with a fondness of music from back when.  Released on: Domino / Playground" web="http://www.annacalvi.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/anna-calvi/" duration="0" title="Dark, romantic rock with a red lipstick mark." scene="" ros_id="29" artist="Anna calvi" artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.352Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/anna-calvi/id395970545?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="ARG" id="31" description="The Cumbia collective Zizek Club gave a demonstration of modern South American city beats at Roskilde Festival in 2009.   Chancha Via Circuito is one of the key profiles of this powerhouse of Latin beats, electronica and dance.   Pedro Canale demonstrates how traditional cumbia tones can sound differently with an electronic beat, and his interest in dub, IDM and down-tempo is also evident. The musical creations are often from the slow end of the spectrum – equal parts Andes Mountains and buzzing Buenos Aires – and yet difficult to stand still to.  Released on: ZZK Records / import" web="http://chanchaviacircuito.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/chancha-via-circuito/" duration="0" title="Digital cumbia with a pulse at rest." scene="" ros_id="30" artist="Chancha via circuito" artist_initial="C" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.352Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/chancha-via-circuito/id282530467?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="32" description="Saul &quot;Chase&quot; Milton and Will &quot;Status&quot; Kennard are about to become megastars in the arena where drum'n'bass, dubstep, pop and rock collide in spectacular public celebrations.  This year the duo has released its second album, No More Idols – you may already have heard the single &quot;Blind Faith&quot;. In addition, the duo has become popular remixers and producers of, for instance, Jay-Z and Rihanna.  Everyone who enjoyed a hot rave in the company of The Prodigy and/or Pendulum at Roskilde Festival 2010, should, have to – must go to a massive drum'n'bass party with Chase &amp; Status.  Released on: Mercury / Universal" web="http://www.chaseandstatus.co.uk/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/chase-status/" duration="0" title="Hot drum'n'bass party." scene="" ros_id="31" artist="Chase &amp; status" artist_initial="C" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.353Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/chase-status/id121546679?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DE" id="33" description="The German people are known for never doing anything half-heartedly, and the latest star on the German indie sky is no exception.  Chuckamuck plays power pop in such a compelling way that there can hardly be any doubt that the four young Berliners are born into this genre where rules are to piss on, and self-restraint does not exist.  In an awry German fashion, Chuckamuck stumbles over everything from slacker rock, lo-fi and indie rock. They are like a power pop invasion that does not stop until you wave the white flag and just dance along.&amp;nbsp;" web="http://www.myspace.com/therealchuckamuck" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/chuckamuck/" duration="0" title="German power pop without rules." scene="" ros_id="32" artist="Chuckamuck" artist_initial="C" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.353Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/chuckamuck/id333437369?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="34" description="Alternative country folk is still often associated with musicians from the other side of the pond. Cody proves that Danes can easily play the same game as Bonnie ‘Prince’ Billy, Lambchop and Neil Young.  Kaspar Kaae is Cody’s band leader, songwriter and artistic driving force. Single- handedly, he produces Americana-sounding pop hits and performs them with a perfect American accent.  In concert, a whole group of musical esquires join him on stage. This way, Cody’s lonely starting point is turned into a collective experience lifted by violins, lap steel guitar and banjo.  Released on: Slow Shark / VME" web="http://www.myspace.com/codysongs" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/cody-1/" duration="0" title="American-sounding folk pop." scene="" ros_id="33" artist="Cody" artist_initial="C" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.353Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="folk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/cody/id161683599?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="INT" id="35" description="Congo's urban music scene has had a great impact on the Western experimental world of music. Now a handful of acclaimed alternative bands go on stage together with the black veterans from Kinshasa and environs.  With Congotronics vs Rockers, the two central congotronics bands Konono N°1 and Kasai Allstars revive their sound in new interpretations along with Deerhoof, Juana Molina, Wildbirds &amp; Peacedrums and Skeletons.  Together, this bunch rediscovers the electrified, joyous trance sound that has turned Congo into a music mecca for hipsters and music lovers.  Released on: Crammed Disc / Cosmos Music Group" web="http://ctvsr.tumblr.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/congotronics-vs-rockers-feat-konono-n1-deerhoof-kasai-allstars-juana-molina-wildbirds-peace/" duration="0" title="Congo trance meets alternative rock." scene="" ros_id="34" artist="Congotronics vs rockers feat. konono n°1, deerhoof, kasai allstars, juana molina, wildbirds &amp; peacedrums and skeletons" artist_initial="C" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.354Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="trance" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="36" description="Chris Cunningham's music videos have fascinated, frightened and amused a whole generation with their dark insanity and ingenuity.  The Aphex Twin videos are pure psychedelic nightmares, and in the video for Björk's &quot;All Is Full of Love&quot; Cunningham shows how the message of the song includes both androids and robots.  The long-haired sci-fi fan now moves even closer to music. With three big screens and a laser show, Chris Cunningham is DJ/VJ in some kind of audiovisual total theater.  Film, concert, mixtape and art installation in one dark show. " web="http://chriscunningham.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/chris-cunningham-live/" duration="0" title="Multimedia show filled with horror and beauty." scene="" ros_id="35" artist="Chris cunningham" artist_initial="C" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.354Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="horror" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/chris-cunningham/id25267839?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="37" description="What do you need crisp bills for when you can rap about them instead? The rapper with the dollar sign in his name has taken the long road towards his current status as a future star – from Lil Wayne’s cash-rich Young Money label to doing it himself.  Curren$y is from New Orleans. You can feel it in the distinctive southern sense of luxurious sounds, making even the swampiest rap about almost nothing seem grandiose.  The backingtrack of corny horns, synths and soul make a perfect match for rap that is laid-back, stoned and full of love of hip hop rather than money.  Released on: Warner Bros " web="http://www.myspace.com/flyspitta" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/curreny/" duration="0" title="Laid-back hip hop about dope, dames and dollars." scene="" ros_id="36" artist="Curren$y" artist_initial="C" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.355Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="hippop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/curren-y/id5914039?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="38" description="&quot;I've only got a seventh-grade education, but I have got a doctorate in funk, and I like to put that to good use.&quot;  The words come from funk legend James Brown who quickly found out that music – especially funk and soul – gave him everything that school and rest of society could not. He shared this approach with L.A.-based musician Dãm Funk, famous for being the boogie-funk ambassador of California.  Like a young Prince, Dãm Funk lives and breathes to keep familiar funk genres of the 80s alive while at the same time leading them all into a musical zeitgeist where everything is more cutting-edge. He is backed by Master Blazter.&amp;nbsp;   Released on: Stones Throw / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/damfunk" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/dam-funk-with-master-blazter/" duration="0" title="Californian funk ambassador with a stylish touch." scene="" ros_id="37" artist="Dãm funk with master blazter" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.355Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="funk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/dam-funk/id263629512?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="39" description="60% American prairie, 40% Eastern European pavement – 100 years ago. This is just about the sound of Dark Dark Dark who paints bygone worlds by means of beautifully orchestrated chamber pop.  Cello, accordion, guitar and piano are just some of the components of this archaic sound world. The band's instrument park takes up some space on stage. Yet, the experience is, above all, intimate, personal and melancholy.  Nona Marie Invie and Marshall LaCount are the band's songwriters and vocalists. Together they build Dark Dark Dark’s beautiful, eclectic music in short and dark stories. " web="http://brightbrightbright.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/dark-dark-dark/" duration="0" title="Antique, richly orchestrated chamber pop." scene="" ros_id="38" artist="Dark dark dark" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.356Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/dark-dark-dark/id420892764?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="40" description="Two of Denmark’s strongest songwriters stand shoulder to shoulder in De Eneste To. The duo is shaped by Nephew front man Simon Kvamm and popular singer/songwriter Peter Sommer.  The two buddies let each other's talents shine in many new ways, and the debut album from 2010 has already spawned several radio hits. De Eneste To create their melodic sounds from traditional rock with electronic beats and quirky ideas, and the final result sounds both familiar and refreshingly new.  Released on: Copenhagen Records / Sony Music" web="http://deenesteto.dk/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/de-eneste-to/" duration="0" title="Two popular Danish songwriters take a crooked break." scene="" ros_id="39" artist="De eneste to" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.356Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/de-eneste-to/id387034784?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="41" description="De Høje Hæle have stolen quite a few hearts in the Copenhagen underground – and perhaps also way outside of Denmark.  Even though De Høje Hæle sing their old-school punk rock in Danish, they have toured extensively throughout Europe, America and Australia. This shows that good music does not care about language.  De Høje Hæle will start you up with a round of rascal punk with lots of attitude.  Released on: Hjernespind" web="http://www.myspace.com/dehjehle" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/de-hoeje-haele/" duration="0" title="Naive and 101 % unpretentious rascal punk." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="40" artist="De høje hæle" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.356Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="punk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/id403535528?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="CAN" id="42" description="The electronic artist Joel Zimmer's star has grown steadily. The pseudonym Deadmau5 has become a synonym for out-of-the-body parties in the proud tradition of bands such as Daft Punk.  Zimmerman calls his concerts 'technological orgies' – and the mouse’s head has reportedly just been upgraded in an LED version.  Techno, house, trance and electro are just some of the components in a session with the smiling mouse who brought down Roskilde Festival’s Cosmopol stage in 2009.  Deadmau5 in 2011 is an upgraded, even wilder experience – a journey into the heart of Zimmerman's high-tech party vision.  Released on: Mau5trap / EMI" web="http://www.deadmau5.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/deadmau5-1/" duration="0" title="Electronic dance orgy." scene="" ros_id="41" artist="Deadmau5" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.357Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/deadmau5/id78011850?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="43" description="Put on your shiniest black dancing shoes. You will not find a better guide into the big city’s dark musical centrifuge than Matthew Dear.  This American DJ, producer and songwriter is a multi faceted figure. He delivers steely hard techno beats under aliases such as Jabberjaw and Audion, and chilled experimental pop under his own name.  Matthew Dear’s latest album Black City underlines his multi-lane motorway with indications of minimal techno, Roxy Music and LCD Soundsystem.  Released on: Ghostly International" web="http://www.matthewdear.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/matthew-dear-live-band/" duration="0" title="Sophisticated urban pop with an electronic pulse." scene="" ros_id="42" artist="Matthew dear – live band" artist_initial="M" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.358Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/matthew-dear/id6947989?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="CAN" id="44" description="Dan Bejar has since the mid-90s released some of the most delicate and enigmatic albums. He also plays in New Pornographers and Swan Lake. But it is with Destroyer that you can experience this Canadian wizard’s eccentric glam pop in full size.  On his latest album Kaputt, Bejar and his sizeable backing band flirt, almost improperly, with soft rock, synths and saxophone solos. However, Destroyer always sounds unique – not least because of the peculiar vocals and the lyrical universe that constructs an entire mythology using references to pop culture, highbrow literature and Bejar's own lyrics.  Released on: Merge / VME" web="http://www.destroyersongs.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/destroyer/" duration="0" title="Eccentric glam pop from one of Canada's greatest songwriters." scene="" ros_id="43" artist="Destroyer" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.359Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/destroyer/id5455211?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="45" description="Jace Clayton aka DJ /Rupture is a busy man. Besides being an internationally renowned DJ, he is a record label owner, radio host, journalist, blogger, speaker, guest lecturer at Harvard University and plays in the band Nettle.  Musically, he is also hard to pigeonhole. He started playing in the drum'n'bass collective Toneburst in Boston in the late 90s. At the same time he began performing as a DJ, and he was known for mixing and combining everything from hip hop and noise to contemporary classical and South American folk music.  His DJ set is in a league of its own and includes three turntables on which he creates complex and subtle mixes including a capalla, breakbeat and ambient effects.  The act plays as part of the The Ex curation on the Pavilion stage. Released on: Tigerbeat6 / import" web="http://www.negrophonic.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/dj-rupture/" duration="0" title="Versatile talent on three turntables." scene="" ros_id="44" artist="Dj /rupture" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.359Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/dj-rupture/id251725382?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="FR" id="46" description="DOP has in short time become one of France's most wanted electronic acts. A position they have fought and worked hard for through countless appearances on big and small European music festivals.  The trio is famous – perhaps even infamous – for its concerts that are a sort electronic grab bag with all sorts of delicious and impulsive ideas, from chill-out and house to hip hop and rock'n'roll. Without ever compromising the electronic base.  DOP's stated mission is to prove that electronica concerts also dare to reach out from the stage, so get ready for a revolutionary concert experience. " web="http://www.myspace.com/dopdopdop" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/dop/" duration="0" title="Party both on and in front of the stage." scene="" ros_id="45" artist="Dop" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.359Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/dop/id266813141?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="47" description="The extreme metal genre has its share of fundamentalists who prefer that the music does not deviate too much from the scripture. Dååth belongs to extreme metal’s more curious minds.  In the course of four albums, the American band has investigated the borderland between death metal, thrash and whichever musical impressions that have caught their interest.&amp;nbsp; Dååth’s two guitarists turn each concert into an eye-opener regarding virtuosity and dizzying solos, while drummer Kevin Talley is a star in metal circles for his take-no-prisoners drumming.  Released on: Century Media / EMI" web="http://www.myspace.com/daath" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/daaaath/" duration="0" title="Unorthodox death metal." scene="" ros_id="46" artist="Dååth" artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.359Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/daath/id178617554?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="48" description="As the son of Steve Earle one could easily remain the guy with the famous father. Yet, Justin Townes Earle seems convincing in his insistence of marking his own territory.  With a rough life behind him, Earle has lots of material to write songs from, loaded with the isolation and hard-earned experiences of country music. At the same time it is clear to hear that this is a new generation singing. As a member of the mp3 generation he can easily skip between different genres such as blues, folk, hillbilly and honky tonk.  Earle junior is at once loyal and unpretentious when he leads classic, American songwriting into the new millennium.  Released on: Bloodshot" web="http://www.justintownesearle.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/justin-townes-earle/" duration="0" title="Versatile country music for the next generation. " scene="" ros_id="47" artist="Justin townes earle" artist_initial="J" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.360Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="country" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/justin-townes-earle/id216060599?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="49" description="The Eclectic Moniker brings summer for your ears and Afro beats for your feet with their calypso-inspired indie rock. And the band has no less than nine members!  It takes that many to achieve such a voluminous and puzzling sound. The Eclectic Moniker is a musical playground – a place where rules are broken and curiosity takes over.&amp;nbsp;" web="http://theeclecticmoniker.bandcamp.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/the-eclectic-moniker/" duration="0" title="Rule breaking indie lads." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="48" artist="The eclectic moniker" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.360Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="indie" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="50" description="John Tchicai is a quite famous gentleman. Not only has he recorded with John Lennon and John Coltrane – the Danish-American saxophonist has also been awarded a lifetime grant from the Danish Ministry of Culture, which gives him freedom to challenge the frames of interaction between world music, jazz and electronica.  John Tchicai gets ample opportunity to explore especially the latter when he steps on stage with the Danish four-piece Elektro. Together, the five musical adventurers go on a trip that leads them through the three genres' most intricate recesses, from familiar territory to new discoveries.  Released on: VME" web="http://www.larswinberg.dk/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/elektro-feat-john-tchicai/" duration="0" title="Adventurism in all corners of jazz." scene="" ros_id="49" artist="Elektro feat. john tchicai" artist_initial="E" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.360Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="jazz" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/elektro/id430180630?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="51" description="You know you must have done something right in the upbringing of your child if she all of a sudden at the tender age of 19 reveals herself as Denmark’s new queen of acid rock.  That is what Emma Acs’ parents must think of their ginger-haired offspring who has already made Danish critics swoon over her trippy and contagious 60s psychedelic music with plenty of room for sitar, Farfisa organs and hippie phrases.&amp;nbsp;  Released on: A:larm" web="http://www.emmaacs.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/emma-acs/" duration="0" title="Teenage talent from the school of psychedelica.  " scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="50" artist="Emma acs" artist_initial="E" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.360Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/emma-acs/id416783905?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="52" description="Nobody knows what has been poured in the water in ​​the Danish town of Ålborg to make it such a fertile breeding ground for Danish metal. However, it does not require repeated listening to Essence’s debut album Lost in Violence before you realise that they are doing something right. Filled with aggression, passion and sing-along-choruses Essence digs 80s’ thrash and manages to add complexity and musical depth to the legendary genre. " web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/essence/" duration="0" title="Flirts with 80s thrash." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="51" artist="Essence" artist_initial="E" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.366Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="NL" id="53" description="They chose the band name because it is quickly spray-painted on a wall. 30 years and countless lineups later, The Ex is still a completely independent, autonomous punk band with the political anger intact.  The starting point is manic post-punk with British-sounding talking vocals, crackling guitars, syncopated drums and an inclination for jazzy improvisation.  But as true musical globetrotters, the Dutchmen have also shared both stage and recording studio with influential musicians from Africa and the US.  We salute The Ex and their Roskilde-like embrace of the world by letting them curate an entire afternoon on Pavilion.  When their guests have played, The Ex will take the stage and give a demonstration of their anarchic, energetic music activism. " web="http://www.theex.nl/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/the-ex-1/" duration="0" title="Post-punk with a global outlook." scene="" ros_id="52" artist="The ex with roy paci" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.366Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="punk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/the-ex/id23499655?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="54" description="A disgusting, sodden monster rises from the Southern swamp. Angrier and higher on pot than ever before. Eyehategod is back.  Their Southern-state-drawling update of Black Sabbath and Melvins has long since made the band an important reference among lovers and practitioners of the metal genre.  Now the band is ready with its first studio album since Confederacy of Ruined Lives from 2000. After years of hardships – including hurricanes and prison sentences – Eyehategod is ready to tear at your ears with a round of tormented and tough metal.  Released on: Century Media / EMI" web="http://eyehategod.ee/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/eyehategod/" duration="0" title="Evil, swampy Southern metal." scene="" ros_id="53" artist="Eyehategod" artist_initial="E" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.367Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/eyehategod/id21479131?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="CD" id="55" description=" He is one of Central Africa's greatest R&amp;B stars – some even call him Africa's Craig David. And Fally Ipupa does have a huge potential in the West with his inspiring pop music.   At the same time, it is always clear with this award-winning artist that we are not in the US on the seat of a glittering sports car. There are plenty of African scents in Ipupa's skilfully composed music, drawing on especially the Congolese rumba soukous that always takes care of the fat combustion with both the audience and the large orchestra that the Congolese like to bring.   Fally Ipupa shows how Africa maybe one day can appear on equal footing with the West on the international charts. Here is an abundance of musical talent – also of well-written R&amp;B.  Released on: Obouo / import" web="http://www.fallyipupaworld.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/fally-ipupa/" duration="0" title="Central African R&amp;B with a wide appeal." scene="" ros_id="54" artist="Fally ipupa" artist_initial="F" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.367Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rnb" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/fally-ipupa/id208298824?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="56" description="Imagine yourself lying in a Swedish clearing surrounded by red wooden houses. Far away you sense a Caribbean wave lapping against the rocks. Some rocking reggae rythmes.  This mixture seems impossible, yet it is the starting point for Fastpoholmen who call their laid-back acoustic folk songs ’forest reggae’.  The cousins Adam and Dawn Fastholm’s voices match each other perfectly. Together they create genuine Swedish music harmony full of nostalgia and sweetness.  Released on: Free Kids / Target" web="http://www.fastpoholmen.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/fastpoholmen/" duration="0" title="Acoustic reggae from Sweden." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="55" artist="Fastpoholmen" artist_initial="F" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.367Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="acoustic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/fastpoholmen/id434825531?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="57" description="This is danceable rock that you can easily move your feet to. However, Foals are intent on musical experimentation, constantly shaking and challenging the templates of their rock songs.  Here you will find skewed, tricky rhythms, African-inspired guitar playing and some abstract but disturbing lyrics, half shout half sung by front man Yannis Phillipakis.  Foals have a musical pioneering spirit that makes the young Oxford lads a different acquaintance on the UK charts.  Released on: Transgressive / Warner" web="http://www.foals.co.uk/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/foals/" duration="0" title="Dance-friendly art rock." scene="" ros_id="56" artist="Foals" artist_initial="F" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.367Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/foals/id192738057?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="COL" id="58" description="Mario Galeano originally carries the name Frente Cumbiero (cumbia brother) on his own shoulders – but when he visits Roskilde Festival he comes as the band leader of a four-piece. &amp;nbsp; Frente Cumbiero is from the stronghold of cumbia, Colombia, but his versatile nature becomes extra obvious as he soon releases an album in collaboration with the dub master himself, Mad Professor.   Frente Cumbiero takes us on a journey through the many variations of the cumbia genre with instrumental, laptop-based party music that makes your heart jump and your pulse race.  Released on: Honest Jons / Cosmos Music Group" web="http://www.frentecumbiero.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/frente-cumbiero/" duration="0" title="Instrumental cumbia from Bogota." scene="" ros_id="57" artist="Frente cumbiero" artist_initial="F" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.375Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="instrumental" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/frente-cumbiero/id376618232?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="59" description="Danish act Frisk Frugt (fresh fruit) mixes Danish, poetic lyrics with sampled sounds and impressions from travels in West Africa.  But the musical embrace of the world does not stop here. Children's song, homemade instruments, free jazz, noise and avant-garde are stacked on top of the already lopsided genre tower.  With Frisk Frugt you are offered both skewed Danish schlager music and a trip through West Africa's dusty villages.&amp;nbsp; Released on: Yo Yo Oy Oy / Lolita Industri" web="http://www.myspace.com/lolitaindustri" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/frisk-frugt/" duration="0" title="Avant-garde meeting between Danish pop and African magic." scene="" ros_id="58" artist="Frisk frugt" artist_initial="F" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.376Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/frisk-frugt/id392269798?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="60" description="He is DJ'ing almost every Wednesday at Low End Theory, one of the most trendsetting music clubs in Los Angeles. The Gaslamp Killer is part of the same family that has enriched the music world with Flying Lotus and Gonjasufi.  The acid head with the anachronistic mustache is a clever genre mixer who knocks, bends and curves music out of shape. His DJ set is filled with cactus acid, urban beats, jazz and Californian post-dubstep.  The Gaslamp Killer provides you with the electronic sounds from Los Angeles so that you almost feel the Pacific blowing through your hair.  Released on: Brainfeeder / import" web="http://thegaslampkiller.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/the-gaslamp-killer/" duration="0" title="L.A. vibes from a true acid head." scene="" ros_id="59" artist="The gaslamp killer" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.376Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/the-gaslamp-killer/id256070798?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="S" id="61" description="”Lucifer” is the first word uttered from Ghost’s widely talked-about debut album Opus Eponymous. The Swedish heavy-rockers spread the message of the impending arrival of the Antichrist. This without any tomfoolery.&amp;nbsp; The style is ultra-conservative heavy metal that proudly ignores most of the influences from post-1970s hard rock. Black Sabbath, Judas Priest and Mercyful Fate are the godfathers of this round of apocalyptic rock that is equally focused on riffs and on melodies.  To keep music in focus, it is unknown who is actually under the ritual clothing in which the band always performs.  Be warned: Ghost is ready to light the black wax candles.  Released on: Rise Above / Target Distribution" web="http://www.myspace.com/thebandghost" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/ghost/" duration="0" title="Occult, melodic heavy metal." scene="" ros_id="60" artist="Ghost" artist_initial="G" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.376Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="62" description="Gold Panda’s debut album Lucky Shiner – a follow-up on numerous praised and acknowledged remixes and the blog hit Quitters Raga – is a dreamy distillation of samples, hot synths, raspy oriental flutes and crackling underlying layers of synthetic drums.  It has an eclectic and much travelled ring to it, and Gold Panda has in fact lived in Japan, but there is also a sense of homeliness and comfort in the middle of the numerous wild samples.  Gold Panda has moved away from making instrumental hip hop to inhabit his own world of calmm yet playful electronica. " web="http://iamgoldpanda.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/gold-panda/" duration="0" title="Soothing electronica." scene="" ros_id="61" artist="Gold panda " artist_initial="G" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.376Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/gold-panda/id318231925?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="63" description="His releases with The Czars never won the acknowledgement they deserved and John Grant was on the verge of turning his back on music. Against all odds, the solo debut album Queen of Denmark was made against all odds.  Nevertheless, this classic piece of Americana ended up as last year’s dark horse among critically acclaimed successes with its songs about homosexuality and self-loathing wrapped in 70-ish pop.  At Roskilde Festival John Grant serves trimmed versions of his sensitive songs backed up just by a single piano and, naturally, his goose-pimpling tenor. " web="http://www.johngrantmusic.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/john-grant/" duration="0" title="Sensitive piano pop." scene="" ros_id="62" artist="John grant" artist_initial="J" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.376Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/john-grant/id297720131?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="S" id="64" description="If rock really is dead and buried, as critics have often claimed, then Graveyard is fully determined to dig it up and breathe life into it again.  With Hisingen Blues the Swedish band has created a roaring monster of a record – a grim but solid work where stoner grooves and heavy riffs roar along with vocalist Joakim Nilsson.  Graveyard is, in other words, the sound of the first and greatest heavy rock legends of the 70s, and if you have ever mourned the untimely end of rock music, you should absolutely not miss out on Graveyard. Rock thrives with this band.  Released on: Nuclear Blast / Warner" web="http://www.myspace.com/graveyardsongs" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/graveyard/" duration="0" title="A slap in the face for all rock refusers." scene="" ros_id="63" artist="Graveyard" artist_initial="G" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.377Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/graveyard/id267826523?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="65" description="Fans of alternative rock in the great American tradition ought to give Hammonds, Harrington &amp;amp; Destroy a listen.  This four-piece is working on putting out its first EP. Judging on the first leaks from the recordings, we can look forward to lots of catchy hits delivered with a reckless, almost punk-rock attitude. " web="http://www.myspace.com/hhdestroyforever" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/hammonds-harrington-destroy/" duration="0" title="Alternative, melodic rock." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="64" artist="Hammonds, harrington &amp; destroy" artist_initial="H" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.377Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="N" id="66" description="Norway has an exciting, young punk band.  Six lads under the age of 20 who can play punk and make it sound – despite all the Norwegian oil millions – of 1977, mass unemployment and frayed leather jackets.  However, these young punk rebels are far from orthodox. Beautiful organ and cello sounds blend seamlessly in on their debut EP that has made enthusiastic Norwegian critics proclaim Honningbarna the saviours of rock – and perhaps of their souls.  Released on: Karmakosmetix / import" web="http://honningbarna.no/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/honningbarna/" duration="0" title="Anarchic teen punk from southern Norway." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="65" artist="Honningbarna" artist_initial="H" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.377Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/honningbarna/id394116593?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="67" description="R&amp;B is more than hot chocolate beauties on MTV. Tom Krell has his own take on the genre.  With his reverb-drenched falsetto voice as the primary instrument, the American philosophy scholar dissolves the genre and discovers a dream-inducing texture underneath.  How To Dress Well is a challenging and welcome renewal of a genre that many loves and loves to hate. Breathtakingly beautiful music comes out of the seemingly inaccessible sounds. Very far from and yet in flirtation with the pop music from the charts.  Released on: Lefse / import" web="http://howtodresswell.blogspot.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/how-to-dress-well/" duration="0" title="Abstract, alternative R&amp;B." scene="" ros_id="66" artist="How to dress well" artist_initial="H" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.377Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rnb" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/how-to-dress-well/id384909913?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="N" id="68" description="Melodies + noise = heaven. If you can concur with this equation, I Was a King is your kind of band.  The Norwegians with the melancholic band name are audibly inspired by the 90s noise rock scene, but add a 60s-ish element of an evergreen innocence and honey-marinated melodies.  Front man Frode Strømstad is the centre from where the good tunes are pouring. Fans of Norwegian music will also spot people from Harrys Gym and 120 Days in the line-up.  I Was A King’s British/American influenced sound is a round of roughly grounded sugar for your ears.  Released on: Sounds Familyre / VME" web="http://iwasaking.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/i-was-a-king/" duration="0" title="Pop gems wrapped in noise." scene="" ros_id="67" artist="I was a king" artist_initial="I" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.381Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/i-was-a-king/id413912843?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="69" description="Danish punk rock takes a great leap forward right now. Four lads from Copenhagen take the longest jumps.  Iceage took our Pavilion Junior stage last year with their clattering post-punk.  The band's first album fully meets the early expectations. Danish critics rejoice over New Brigade, a darkened post-punk album full of sharp guitars, tumbling drums and apathetic doom lyrics. 1977 multiplied by 2011. Iceage’s chaotic music sounds like the start of a new frost-filled golden age.  Released on: Tambourhinoceros / Escho / Playground" web="http://www.iceagecopenhagen.blogspot.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/iceage-1/" duration="0" title="Intense, uncontrolled post-punk." scene="" ros_id="68" artist="Iceage" artist_initial="I" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.381Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="punk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/iceage/id406846711?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="ETH" id="70" description="Ililta Band is based in the Ethiopian capital Addis Ababa and was formed by singer and masingo player Chalachew Ashenafi. He started his career playing at bars and performing at day-long wedding celebrations among wealthy Ethiopians where Ashenafi got a reputation for being able to kick-start any party. His popularity grew when he began sending out tapes.  In 2009 he released his first CD and began touring as a trio with Ililta Band who in addition to masingo uses traditional African instruments such as krar and kebero.  The trio knows how to deliver a positive and intimate atmosphere that exudes exotic tribal celebrations and African hospitality.  The act plays as part of the The Ex curation on the Pavilion stage." web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/ililta-band/" duration="0" title="Ethiopian wedding party and tribal dance." scene="" ros_id="69" artist="Ililta band" artist_initial="I" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.381Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="african" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="71" description="An unforgettable round of Maiden is in store for the audience at the Roskilde Festival. The heavy metal legends’ recapturing of the Orange Stage will be the band’s only festival concert in Scandinavia this summer.  Iron Maiden’s new album, The Final Frontier, shows a group of musicians who, in spite of having played nearly 2,000 concerts, still holds a firm grip of their instruments. The same goes for an untiring audience who greets the British heroes with their arms raised high in the air in almost every part of the world.  The hellfire, the theatrical refrains, the wind-swept sensation;&amp;nbsp; the entire riff-packed&amp;nbsp; Valkyrie ride is still intact in Iron Maiden after 30 years as one of the most important heavy rock bands.  Released on: EMI Music" web="http://www.ironmaiden.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/iron-maiden-3/" duration="0" title="Legendary, long-haired heavy metal." scene="" ros_id="70" artist="Iron maiden" artist_initial="I" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.381Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/iron-maiden/id546381?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="72" description="The just 21-year-old American has already been dubbed electronic music’s big American hope.  Nicolas Jaar’s music is both focused on rhythm and repetition while giving room for lots of musical frills. He moves in and out of electro pop, Afro jazz, sound collages, hip hop and many other styles – all tied together by his melancholy vocal.  Nicolas Jaar is inventive and curious but he also completely on top of things when it comes to the electronic genre’s very finest effects. &amp;nbsp; Released on: Clown and Sunset / import" web="http://www.nicolasjaar.net/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/nicolas-jaar/" duration="0" title="Electronic minimalism with lots of frills." scene="" ros_id="71" artist="Nicolas jaar" artist_initial="N" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.382Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/nicolas-jaar/id301995668?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="73" description="Something peculiar and highly alluring is going on when British Jackdaw with Crowbar is on stage. The band plays some kind of psychedelic post-punk with dark disco synths and a singer cackling like a chicken. The backdrop displays disturbing visuals of floating heads and dancing giant lobsters, reminiscent of David Lynch and Tim Burton's surreal worlds.   Jackdaw with Crowbar was formed in 1986, and the band released three albums and recorded two of the legendary BBC Peel Sessions before breaking up in 1992. After a 15-year-long break the group reformed in 2007 and as recently as last year they released a live EP.   It is, however, on stage that you get the full benefit of raving Brits. Look forward to this – a surprisingly bizarre experience awaits!  The act plays as part of the The Ex curation on the Pavilion stage." web="http://www.jackdawwithcrowbar.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/jackdaw-with-crowbar/" duration="0" title="Psychedelic post-punk with crazy visuals." scene="" ros_id="72" artist="Jackdaw with crowbar" artist_initial="J" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.382Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="punk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="TAN" id="74" description="They play most of their concerts on street corners after weddings in Dar Es Salaam, and their current back catalog is only out on cassette tapes.  Jagwa Music from Tanzania cultivates a genre called mchiriku, a percussion-based type of music that makes your blood boil with its steady, rhythmic attack. Due to a lack of funds, the musicians use old Casio keyboards and whatever materials they can get a hold of as well as traditional African drums.  The experience is still luxurious when Jagwa Music in a dancy and acrobatic stage show gets the audience to raise their arms in excitement.  Released on: Jahazi Media / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/jagwamusicmchiriku" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/jagwa-music/" duration="0" title="Raw drum music from Dar Es Salaam's poor suburbs." scene="" ros_id="73" artist="Jagwa music" artist_initial="J" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.382Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="african" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/jagwa/id39980021?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="75" description="Tomas Barfod (WhoMadeWho) crosses swords with Jakob Littauer and Mads Kolding (Electrojuice) in Jatoma.   The collaboration of the two young boys and the slightly older star producer was really mostly for fun. But no. The music was picked up in Cologne, and soon the trio was signed to the exclusive German label Kompakt, home of some of the biggest buffs from the electronic scene.   Jatoma is an exciting direction for everyone involved. Minimal techno, found sounds, impressionistic synthesizers. Everything drifts easily together and apart again in a picturesque absorbent sound cosmos, boosting both daydreaming and an urge to dance.  Released on: Fake Diamond / A:larm" web="http://www.myspace.com/jatoma" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/jatoma/" duration="0" title="Organic, dreamy techno." scene="" ros_id="74" artist="Jatoma" artist_initial="J" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.382Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="techno" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/jatoma/id386771223?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="76" description="They have played together for 30 years on a mixture of gall, doomsday readiness and general pessimism.  With industrial synths, aggressive guitars and electronic techno rhythms, Killing Joke has inspired a dizzying number of bands. Both the metal and punk crowds have embraced this band who with legendary Jaz Coleman in front has one of the many relentlessly unique front men of the British rock scene.  Absolute Dissent from 2010 is made with the original lineup from the late 70s and shows a manic top form on par with back then.  Released on: Spine Farm / Cosmos Music Group" web="http://www.killingjoke.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/killing-joke-1/" duration="0" title="Apocalyptic, electronic post-punk." scene="" ros_id="75" artist="Killing joke" artist_initial="K" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.382Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="punk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/killing-joke/id14548963?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="77" description="The preacher's sons in Kings of Leon were brought up among Tennessee pickup-trucks and leather-bound Bibles.  Since their fourth album – the breakthrough Only by the Night – things have progressed rapidly, and Kings of Leon are no longer just for fans of alternative country rock with a Southern flavour. Today the whole world sings along to hits such as &quot;Sex On Fire&quot; and &quot;Use Somebody&quot;.  The band visited Roskilde Festival for the first time in 2004. In 2011 we welcome them back as the US answer to U2 – and with a long-awaited new rock album, Come Around Sundown, that, according to the band itself, should satisfy both new and old fans.  Prepare for a stadium rock experience full of American country roads and a proud music tradition.  Released on: Sony Music" web="http://www.kingsofleon.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/kings-of-leon-2/" duration="0" title="Stadium rock with a Southern flavour." scene="" ros_id="76" artist="Kings of leon" artist_initial="K" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.383Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/kings-of-leon/id1883403?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="78" description="They still live with their parents but Kirsten &amp;amp; Marie shoot up with their innocent and forest floor-scented folk pop.  The Danish twins have stolen the heart of a whole nation with &quot;My Dear&quot;, an incredibly effective pop song with a simple, childlike refrain.  Let your heart be charmed by beautiful vocals and dreamy tunes from two true natural talents.  Released on: Tambourhinoceros / Playground" web="http://kirstenmarie.net/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/kirsten-marie/" duration="0" title="Acoustic guitar and adorable maiden vocals." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="77" artist="Kirsten &amp; marie" artist_initial="K" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.383Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="acoustic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/kirsten-marie/id364354747?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="N" id="79" description=" When guitarist Robert Burås died at the age of only 31 in 2007 – with the guitar in his hand –the Norwegian rock scene lost one of its greatest musicians.  Now, several of Burås' former bandmates from Madrugada, Richochets and Burås' own side project My Midnight Creeps have gotten together in Kitchie Kitchie Ki Me O, which – besides being a living tribute to their friend – is Norway's biggest musical hope in 2011.  The band consists of members from all three bands&amp;nbsp;and plays hard-hitting rock with lots of guitar. Chances are good of a high-quality concert experience, maybe even as good as when Madrugada played Roskilde. " web="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Kitchie-Kitchie-Ki-Me-O/185337610403" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/kitchie-kitchie-ki-me-o/" duration="0" title="Norwegian supergroup with wounds to the soul." scene="" ros_id="78" artist="Kitchie kitchie ki me o" artist_initial="K" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.383Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/kitchie-kitchie-ki-me-o/id436564634?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="80" description="Mystics from the 14th century are a rare sight on the Danish music scene. Kloster (Danish for monastery) belongs to a different category. Mikael R Andreasen is the centre of the project.  On his latest release, The Waves and Winds Still Know His Voice, lyrics and themes are borrowed from Julian of Norwich, an English seer who rose up to her God around 1416. With this remote background, a unique, meditative atmosphere arises with poetry and beauty flowing from it.  Andreasen’s songs are mainly acoustic and sparing of words but rich on instrumental variations – full of spiritual aspiration and delicate desperation. &amp;nbsp;  Released on: Washington Inc / VME" web="http://www.myspace.com/klosterincyberspace" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/kloster/" duration="0" title="Spiritual folk filled with mysticism and beauty." scene="" ros_id="79" artist="Kloster" artist_initial="K" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.383Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="folk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/kloster/id339652763?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DE" id="81" description="Some people manage to be good at almost everything – resulting in equal parts admiration and irritation for the rest of us.   DJ Koze seems to be one of those types with a lengthy resume. He has been active since the 90s and made ​​everything from electro house to hip hop. Dance, disco and tech house are just the superficial mission description with this electronic Renaissance man.   DJ Koze’s sets are rock-solid German electronic class following the proud tradition of connoisseur label Kompakt. But you also find surprising genre leaps and style shifts, dissolving any preconception about the German soul as gray, mathematical and humourless.  Released on: Kompakt / VME" web="http://www.djkoze.de/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/dj-koze/" duration="0" title="Genre-hostile tech house." scene="" ros_id="80" artist="Dj koze " artist_initial="D" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.383Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="techno" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/dj-koze/id93239996?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="NGA" id="82" description="As son of Fela Kuti he has carried on his father's legacy to a huge audience who rejoice over this incredibly hot and sexy music. He started out as a member of his father's band back in the 80s.  Today he plays with his own fourteen-piece band, Positive Force. Here he combines sharp-edged rhythms with Miles/Gillespie-inspired brass and seductive dancers. All this in one and the same awesome show.  His fourth appearance at Roskilde Festival is out of the ordinary. After a concert with his faithful band, Positive Force, Femi plays together with younger brother Seun Kuti – for the first time ever.  A historic Afrobeat celebration awaits.  Released on: Wrasse / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/femikuti" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/femi-kuti-positive-force/" duration="0" title="Afrobeat in new bottles." scene="" ros_id="81" artist="Femi kuti &amp; positive force" artist_initial="F" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.384Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="african" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/femi-kuti/id399130?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="NGA" id="83" description="He is the youngest son of Afro-beat pioneer Fela Kuti. Today Seun Anikulapo Kuti plays with Fela’s old backing band Egypt ’80 – and a new Brian Eno-produced album sees the light of day in 2011.  The red-hot mix of funk, sparkling brass, musical joy and political indignation continues – yet, Kuti junior relates just as much to the present music scene as he does to his iconic family name.  He follows up on his dazzling Roskilde concert in 2007 – in addition, he shares the limelight with big brother Femi Kuti.  The two sons of the great Kuti on the same stage is never seen before. He must surely tap his foot in the heaven of music legends while this historic Afro-beat party takes place.  Released on: Knitting Factory / VME" web="http://www.myspace.com/seunkuti" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/seun-anikulapo-kuti-egypt-80/" duration="0" title="Afrobeat grooves from 2011." scene="" ros_id="82" artist="Seun anikulapo kuti &amp; egypt 80" artist_initial="S" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.384Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="african" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/egypt-80/id426268125?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="84" description="Many metal fans already know Kylesa as a productive band with five albums under the belt since 2002. Fans of Pink Floyd and At the Drive-In ought to also give the Georgia band a chance.  Make no mistake: This is bad Southern metal with hungry vultures and impoverished desert soil. But the band's double drums attack, the vocal alternation between Laura Pleasants and Philip Cope and the many accessible and almost indie-rocking features of the songs make Kylesa a band who, as a matter of course, invites all kinds of music lovers into the fold.  Here the newly initiatied can experience how gruesomely they can rock out in the Southern states.  Released on: Season of Mist / Target Distribution" web="http://www.kylesa.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/kylesa/" duration="0" title="Psychedelic metal with a wide appeal." scene="" ros_id="83" artist="Kylesa" artist_initial="K" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.384Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/kylesa/id26094346?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="S" id="85" description="Sweet pop music is easily combined with an experimental temper. Little Dragon is proof of that.  The quirky pop band never resigns itself to just pleasing – it constantly explores texture, rhythms and melodic patterns so that the expression is constantly changing.  Yukimi Nagano is fronting the band. With this charismatic singer (last seen at Roskilde Festival together with Gorillaz in 2010) the band has an extra ace, making the mixture of synth pop, jazzy R&amp;B and trip hop particularly appealing.  Little Dragon has collaborated with capacities such as Damon Albarn and Dave Sitek from TV On The Radio. This indicates which musical vitamins are to be found in the body of the small band from Gothenburg.  Released on: Peacefrog / VME" web="http://www.little-dragon.se/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/little-dragon/" duration="0" title="Playful, electronic pop." scene="" ros_id="84" artist="Little dragon" artist_initial="L" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.384Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/little-dragon/id258535972?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="S" id="86" description="The Swedish language is made for cute girl pop. Just have a listen to Little Marbles.  Rumour has it that the two young ladies performed their first concert at one of the girls' grandmother’s birthday party. Since then, they have charmed a much bigger – and tougher – audience with their acoustic, easy-going and sweet pop music. And with great success.  Even Mike Patton from Faith No More has given them a thumbs up at a Swedish music festival.  Released on: Nation / import" web="http://littlemarbles.blogg.se/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/little-marbles/" duration="0" title="Cheerful, acoustic pop." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="85" artist="Little marbles" artist_initial="L" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.384Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="acoustic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/little-marbles/id281773007?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="87" description="He has become somewhat of an institution at Roskilde Festival and in the Danish Kingdom. L.O.C. brought down the Orange Stage singlehandedly in 2008, and he has been a guest rapper at Roskilde concerts with Petter, Tech N9ne and Nephew.&amp;nbsp;  Now, the king of Danish hip hop is ready with a brand new album, Libertiner, which should be his most personal album yet. With more than 200,000 albums sold the expectations are high. But the Irish-Danish rapper hasn’t let down his numerous fans who love Liam O’Connor for his magnificent flow and twists of the Danish language inspired by his American role models.  Let your caps follow the rhythm when his highness L.O.C. is treating us with his honest hip hop.  Released on: Virgin / EMI" web="http://www.loc.nu/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/loc-3/" duration="0" title="The king of Danish hip hop" scene="" ros_id="86" artist="L.o.c." artist_initial="L" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.385Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="hiphop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/l-o-c/id15026807?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="88" description="The last few years have not been easy for fans of Love Shop. In 2008 we lost guitarist Hilmer Hassig in a tragic car accident, and earlier this year Henrik Hall lost the fight against cancer.  So this is Love Shop’s first visit to the festival with Jens Unmack as the only original member. But anyone who has heard one of Love Shop’s concerts during this spring has seen a singer who lively and life-affirmingly steps out of the shadows.  Love Shop’s pop magic has always been greater than the individual members, and the band's sixth concert at Roskilde Festival will be no exception.  Released on: A:larm" web="http://www.jensunmack.dk/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/love-shop-5/" duration="0" title="Danish pop music outshining a tragedy." scene="" ros_id="87" artist="Love shop" artist_initial="L" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.385Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/love-shop/id58774590?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="N" id="89" description="Great songs sprout like oil from the Norwegian underground.  Lukestar is one of the most important bands from the Norway’s alternative scene, and the band’s latest record Lake Toba has reaped tons of praise.  Lead singer Truls Heggero has an high pitched, frail voice and the rest of the band create angelic melodies and turbulent arrangements that sound as if they were made from a unique mixture of inland ice and helium.  With Lukestar, Norway has a worthy cousin to other Nordic worshippers of beauty such as Mew and Sigur Rós.  Released on: Tuba / Import" web="http://www.lukestar.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/lukestar/" duration="0" title="Melodious falsetto pop." scene="" ros_id="88" artist="Lukestar" artist_initial="L" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.385Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="S" id="90" description="She last played at Roskilde Festival in 2008. With her ​​youthful, light voice and symmetrical face, for many Lykke Li was the epitome of a happy Scandinavian.  Wounded Rhymes – the critically acclaimed, cloudy album number two from this year – shows an artist who has lost her puppy fat. And although the Swede's entry into the adult world has left some marks on her heart, we as the audience should be excited about the new Lykke Li.  Inspired by especially classic, Phil Spector/Motown-esque pop music, she has created a record full of substance and melody. An album that bodes well for a concert full of catchy tunes and feminine power in the proud Swedish tradition.  Released on: LL Recordings / EMI" web="http://www.lykkeli.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/lykke-li-1/" duration="0" title="Super Scandinavian black-hearted pop." scene="" ros_id="89" artist="Lykke li" artist_initial="L" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.385Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/lykke-li/id263435943?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="91" description="Roskilde Festival 2008 was part of turning Magnetic Man into what they are today. The response from the audience at their last Roskilde visit was so overwhelming that the three Brits just had to continue.  Magnetic Man has brought the dubstep genre into the mainstream with singles such as &quot;I Need Air&quot; and &quot;Perfect Stranger&quot;. But there are still plenty of bass-loaded atmosphere from the genre's steamy underground when Benga, Skream and Artwork play live.  Magnetic Man show Roskilde Festival their affection by doing a custom-designed, extensive show. Look forward to visits from Katy B and SBTRKT, a boiling party atmosphere and, above all, bass, bass, bass, making the trees at the festival site wobble.  Released on: Sony Music UK / Sony Music" web="http://www.magneticman.net/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/magnetic-man-with-special-guests-katy-b-and-sbtrkt-dj-set/" duration="0" title="Dubstep party custom-designed for Roskilde." scene="" ros_id="90" artist="Magnetic man with special guests katy b and sbtrkt dj set" artist_initial="M" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.385Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/magnetic-man/id309017347?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="COL" id="92" description="Africa and South America are intertwined musically. La Makina Del Karibe is a Colombian music collective, but their primary guiding principle is, according to themselves, soukous, the hot kind of rumba that you particularly associate with Congo and Central Africa.   However, this is not a clear-cut tribute to the distant neighbors. In the course of five years, La Makina Del Karibe has spread a high pulse and party atmosphere at home by combining African sounds and percussion in a fun and schizophrenic blend of champeta, cumbia, punk and ska.   This is the sound of summer.  Released on: Chusma / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/lamakinadelkaribe" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/la-makina-del-karibe/" duration="0" title="Afro-Colombian, unpretentious music collective." scene="" ros_id="91" artist="La makina del karibe" artist_initial="L" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.386Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="african" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/la-makina-del-karibe/id421681469?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="93" description="Johannes Gammelby has explored almost every corner of Danish indie rock.  After excelling with the bands Strumm, I Am Bones and the hard-hitting Beta Satan, Gammelby now goes in a whole new direction with The Malpractice and the album Tectonics.  It is heavy and tight but never without charm and the inclination to take chances.  Released on: Crunchy Frog" web="http://themalpractice.blogspot.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/the-malpractice/" duration="0" title="Shockingly intense rock from Danish indie guru." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="92" artist="The malpractice" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.386Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/the-malpractice/id376177361?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="94" description="With a band name like this, you are almost predestined to become great. Mastodon has played at Roskilde Festival in 2005 and 2007. We welcome them back in 2011 as full-grown metal giants.  Mastodon is on the front line when it comes to complexity, technicality and literary weight – their latest album, Crack the Skye, is about astrology, time travel and the Russian czardom. Meanwhile, the songs become more beautiful and melodic with each new album.  Mastodon stands as a huge profile in the progressive metal scene. Perhaps because they manage to combine the challenging and experimental with a basic joy of fast riffs and heavy grooves.  Released on: Reprise / Warner" web="http://www.mastodonrocks.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/mastodon-2/" duration="0" title="Cosmic prog-metal." scene="" ros_id="93" artist="Mastodon" artist_initial="M" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.386Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/mastodon/id65922937?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="95" description="To Mikkel Bolding, indie folk rock is one big buffet – and believe us when we say that this Danish one-man orchestra is not in lack of an appetite.  This spring, Messy Shelters released his second album Root System – and it is the many jumps between efficient rock equilibrium and monotonous and minimalistic electronica that make this a very interesting listen.  Released on: Tigerspring" web="http://www.facebook.com/messyshelters?sk=app_178091127385" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/messy-shelters/" duration="0" title="A one-man band with an appetite for a bit of everything. " scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="94" artist="Messy shelters" artist_initial="M" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.386Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="96" description="Mathangi ”Maya” Arulpragasam is the daughter of a political activist from Sri Lanka, and in many ways she has followed in her father's revolutionary footsteps.  She calls herself M.I.A. (Missing In Action). Her music is dirty like a city pavement, and it has both Western and Oriental blood running through its system. She&amp;nbsp;skips between the continents in the same way as the rest of us manoeuvre the internet. Dancehall, Bollywood, Afro hip hop, Suicide. Everything is put on the catapult and fired off.  London's grime scene is the starting point. And M.I.A. has long since become a global, provocative phenomenon – equal parts Che Guevara and pop princess with sunglasses. The revolution continues on YouTube, Twitter and WikiLeaks, and M.I.A. delivers the soundtrack with her screaming palette of multi-ethnic pop music.  Released on: XL / Playground" web="http://miauk.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/mia/" duration="0" title="Revolutionary pop icon." scene="" ros_id="95" artist="M.i.a." artist_initial="M" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.386Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/m-i-a/id14677454?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="97" description="She is in the mid-20s, but from which planet? Janelle Monáe’s debut album The ArchAndroid sounds like Fritz Lang's classic silent film Metropolis if it were played as a musical by Stevie Wonder's backing band and a group of indie rockers had dropped by. R&amp;B, soul and alternative rock in an almost rudely perfect choreography.  Janelle Monáe is so larger-than-life that it is almost hard to believe she really exists.  Look forward to experiencing that this is in fact true at Roskilde Festival ­– it will be miss Monaé’s first visit on Danish soil.  Released on: Bad Boy / Warner" web="http://www.jmonae.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/janelle-monae/" duration="0" title="Alternative R&amp;B from another galaxy." scene="" ros_id="96" artist="Janelle monáe" artist_initial="J" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.387Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rnb" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/janelle-monae/id140777342?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="NL" id="98" description="In a short time, Munchi has become one of the global electronic scene's most sought-after names as a DJ and producer.  M.I.A. has invited him along on her latest mixtape Vicki Leekx – and just like the style and pop icon, this Dominican kid from Rotterdam has a mixed background. Perhaps this is one of the reasons for Munchi’s musical palette.  Look forward to a many-coloured DJ set full of dancehall, baile funk, dubstep, and, not least, moombahton – Munchi is one of the main exponents of this brand-new, speeded-down variant of reggaeton. " web="http://munchiproductions.blogspot.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/munchi/" duration="0" title="Tropical ghetto beats." scene="" ros_id="97" artist="Munchi" artist_initial="M" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.387Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/munchi/id381100897?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="SOL" id="99" description="This group is spectacular, even at Roskilde Festival.  The collective consists of a group of natives from the Solomon Islands, located around New Zealand and Australia.  They play the music of their ancestors throughout hundreds of years – authentic, ritual music that imitates nature, animal calls and Pacific waves.  Panpipes in all kinds of sizes and percussion are at the centre when the band dances, blows and drums through terrific concerts – of course delivered in traditional war paint but with a peace-loving atmosphere of nature, brotherhood and well-being.  Released on: Pan People Publishing / import" web="http://www.narasirato.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/narasirato/" duration="0" title="Panpipes collective in full war paint. " scene="" ros_id="98" artist="Narasirato" artist_initial="N" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.387Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="instrumental" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/narasirato-pan-pipers/id269332628?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="N" id="100" description="‘An electronic attack’, ‘chip-core’ and ‘Gameboy-death metal’ are just few examples of the strangely precise descriptions that have been used on Norwegian Next Life the last couple of years.  And the bizarreness does not end here. With guitarist Hai Nguyen Dinh in front, this Oslo trio is probably the first band ever to combine Asian avant-garde electronica and computer game beats with legendary Norwegian metal.  Next Life is as heavy as Mayhem but as colourful as Japanese Manga – and even though the guitar-synth-drums combo has been used several times before we doubt that anyone has done it quite like Next Life.  Released on: Fysisk Format / import" web="http://www.electricdungeon.org/Main_Page.html" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/next-life/" duration="0" title="Gameboy metal" scene="" ros_id="99" artist="Next life " artist_initial="N" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.387Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/next-life/id199105546?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="GRL" id="101" description="Snow, isolation and degrees below zero provide good conditions for the music. This has been proven in Iceland, Norway – and Greenland.  Nive Nielsen’s soothing voice is accompanied by a little red ukulele, and her band The Deer Children add all the best from the American prairie. The inspiration is American but the Eskimo blood flows strongly through Nielsen's veins.  Her first album, Nive Sings, is a bestseller in desolate Greenland and may indicate the birth of a new, icy music mecca.  Released on: Tuttu / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/nivenielsen" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/nive-nielsen-the-deer-children/" duration="0" title="Eskimo folk." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="100" artist="Nive nielsen &amp; the deer children" artist_initial="N" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.513Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="folk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="US" id="102" description="A hip hop sensation rolls like an avalanche through the web’s many music blogs. YouTube is tainted with concert footage of some young hip hoppers who clearly take the genre all the way in a punk direction.  This phenomenon is called OFWGKTA (Odd Future Wolf Gang Kill Them All). Tyler the Creator is the centre of the wolf pack, and around him is a whole formation of young, talented rappers.  The expression is dark, apocalyptic and demonic. Tyler raps about violence, death and necrophilia – but the Los Angeles collective also have humour, gags and subversive activism going for them.  Alternative hip hop has found its strongest voice in a very long time." web="http://oddfuture.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/ofwgkta/" duration="0" title="Sensational hip hop collective from Los Angeles." scene="" ros_id="101" artist="Ofwgkta" artist_initial="O" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.514Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="hiphop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/tyler-the-creator/id420368335?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="103" description="Nanna Øland Fabricius continues conquering new territory. Oh Land has become a prime focus with label giant Sony, and she is now residing in New York. Still, the feel and taste of the Dane's lux-pop is predominantly European.  Oh Land has the song material, the flamboyant looks and the stage presence to compete with today's sophisticated pop divas.  The first international album has just been released. Even though all sorts of expensive producers have had a hand in it, you can still feel the experimental playfulness that has always flowed through Oh Land's twisted, electronic pop.  Released on: Fake Diamond Records / A:larm" web="http://www.ohlandmusic.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/oh-land/" duration="0" title="Electronic lux-pop from international shooting star." scene="" ros_id="102" artist="Oh land" artist_initial="O" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.514Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/oh-land/id292077282?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="MAR" id="104" description=" In Morocco Oadeden easily gathers 100,000 people at their concerts.   The popular band is ambassador for the Berbers, North Africa's indigenous population.   Many of the members have played together since the 80s and are an institution in Moroccan music. Banjo, guitar and infinitely subtle percussion playing are the basic ingredients in the Berbers’ improvisational song cycle about the beauty and agony of life.   Oudaden’s front man Abdellah el Fouah sings in the Berbers’ own dialect tashelhait on top of both complex and festive grooves. " web="http://www.myspace.com/oudaden" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/oudaden/" duration="0" title="North African desert jam on banjo and guitar." scene="" ros_id="103" artist="Oudaden" artist_initial="O" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.514Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="folk" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="BG" id="105" description="One of the greatest masters of the clarinet – perhaps ever – is named Ivo Papasov.   In the 70s he developed a special blend of jazz-coloured party brass music for weddings in his homeland of Bulgaria. Today he is long since canonized as one of the central figures of Roma music.   Western capabilities such as Frank Zappa and David Sanborn have gaped when the Bulgarian master puts his lips to the mouthpiece.   Together with his Wedding Band, Ivo Papasov kicks the door in to a whirlwind of brass, Middle Eastern sounds and almost illogically high tempos.   A true legend holds court.  Released on: Kuker Music" web="http://www.papasov.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/ivo-papasov-his-wedding-band/" duration="0" title="Wedding music fronted by legendary clarinetist." scene="" ros_id="104" artist="Ivo papasov &amp; his wedding band" artist_initial="I" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.514Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="instrumental" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/ivo-papasov/id254697195?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="AUS" id="106" description="With three albums under the belt, Parkway Drive is becoming one of Australia's biggest successes in metal and hardcore. The young band’s first albums were produced by none other than Adam Dutkiewicz from metalcore kings Killswitch Engage. In the future the Australians may just well be in the same league as these metal giants.  Do not let Parkway Drive’s pretty band name fool you. This is metalcore from the angriest and heaviest part of the genre spectrum – with no MTV-friendly choruses to sweeten the pill.  Show up for a round of indignant guitar ripping from down under.  Released on: Epitaph / Cosmos" web="http://www.parkwaydriverock.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/parkway-drive/" duration="0" title="The new metalcore heroes." scene="" ros_id="105" artist="Parkway drive" artist_initial="P" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.515Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/parkway-drive/id166667737?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="107" description="With his 34 years, Per Vers is reaching that age when most other rappers are considering retirement. And as if that was not enough, he is also so happily in love with his wife that he can hardly muster the exaggerated self-satisfaction that has always been the fuel to the flames of hip hop. But instead of sinking into musical indifference and lyrical trivialities, Per Verse has with the album Ego made ​​the most vital move of his career, rhythmically as well as lyrically. So, this is a rap veteran on top of his game, returning to Roskilde Festival – happy, but by no means trivial.  Released on: Mixed Ape Music / Playground" web="http://per.tv/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/per-vers/" duration="0" title="Danish rap icon at the top of his game." scene="" ros_id="106" artist="Per vers" artist_initial="P" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.515Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rap" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/per-vers/id74900330?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="108" description="She is the queen of alternative rock. A chameleon who prefers to wear black or white. Infatuated men and admiring girls got to know her as a tough yet sensitive fury on the early 90’s albums. Later on she has embraced the role of the cool city girl and gothic ballad singer with just as much conviction.&amp;nbsp;  Polly Jean Harvey’s eight opus reaches our shores these days. Let England Shake is a concept album about England’s many wars, primarily written on autoharp – the result being some of her career’s catchiest tunes.  We are proud to have this boundary - seeking rock figure with a thirst for life back at Roskilde Festival.  Released on: Island / Universal" web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/pj-harvey-2/" duration="0" title="The queen of alternative rock." scene="" ros_id="107" artist="Pj harvey" artist_initial="P" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.515Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="109" description="Prince Fatty Soundsystem have proclaimed that they were made to “dub your feet with Rock Steady beats and stimulate brain waves in a jazz-like way”.&amp;nbsp; The mastermind behind the music collective from Brighton is producer Mike Pelanconi who has previously worked with major acts such as Lily Allen, Sugarhill Gang and Blur guitarist Graham Coxon.  Even though Prince Fatty Soundsystem originally was created as a musical ad for a clothing brand, it became such a great success on British airwaves that Pelanconi decided to continue the party with a long line of musicians and singers.&amp;nbsp;  Released on: Mr. Bongo / import" web="http://www.princefatty.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/prince-fatty-soundsystem-feat-little-roy-and-horseman/" duration="0" title="Dub for weary feet." scene="" ros_id="108" artist="Prince fatty soundsystem feat. little roy and horseman" artist_initial="P" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.515Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/prince-fatty/id256308331?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="UK" id="110" description=" Their self-titled debut album from 2010 has been several years in the making. Pulled Apart by Horses have been far too busy making a name for themselves as a perverse, unpredictable and violent live acquaintance.&amp;nbsp;   Pulled Apart by Horses play a festive kind of rock/hardcore hybrid with a penchant for screaming vocals, odd time signatures and short song lengths.   One of the band's many charming features is an unmistakable sense of humour – just look at song titles such as &amp;quot;Back to the Fuck Yeah&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;I Punched a Lion in the Throat&amp;quot;.  Released on: Transgressive / Cosmos Music Group" web="http://www.pulledapartbyhorses.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/pulled-apart-by-horses/" duration="0" title="Party hardcore for the derailed." scene="" ros_id="109" artist="Pulled apart by horses" artist_initial="P" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.515Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/pulled-apart-by-horses/id277134407?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="EGY" id="111" description="Hassan Bergamon is a master of an ancient musical instrument, the rango. This African marimba is, as the band name suggests, one of the fundamental elements in Rango's of Sudanese ceremony music.  With the rango at the center, the lyre-like tanbura and often lavishly costumed dancers, this is unlike anything you will find elsewhere in Egypt – or in the wider world.  We give you a rare opportunity to experience a musical trance, equal parts wizard cult, polyrhythmic percussion and rich slave blues from a band filled with defiant vigour.  Released on: 30IPS / import" web="http://www.30ips.com/rango/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/rango/" duration="0" title="Sudanese cult music on ancient instruments." scene="" ros_id="110" artist="Rango" artist_initial="R" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.516Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="instrumental" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/rango/id327613094?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="112" description="Every time we think that The Raveonettes have reached the end of their quest for the primal source of rock, they take a new step, often in a completely unexpected direction but fortunately always with outstanding results.  With this year's Raven in the Grave, Sharin Foo and Sune Wagner demonstrate new sides of their musical companionship – where emotions are allowed to overshadow the otherwise tight form and where the 80s-like dark and melancholy guitar crunch now live and breathe side by side with the rock'n'roll that started the whole story of Denmark's biggest rock export ever.  Released on: Universal" web="http://www.theraveonettes.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/the-raveonettes-4/" duration="0" title="New sides to an old friendship." scene="" ros_id="111" artist="The raveonettes" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.516Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/the-raveonettes/id654568?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="113" description="Reptile &amp;amp; Retard have already played for much larger audiences than what the Pavilion Junior stage can muster – despite the fact that Esben Valløe and Mads Damsgaard have not yet released their debut album. Last year their insane live show was discovered by Oasis' previous American agent who sent the two Danish electro rock lads on a big Chinese tour." web="http://www.myspace.com/reptileandretard" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/reptile-retard/" duration="0" title="Big in Japan – and around." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="112" artist="Reptile &amp; retard" artist_initial="R" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.516Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="JAM" id="114" description="The reggae scene needs charismatic leaders in a time when the more electronic dancehall genre conquers still more territory.  Tarrus Riley (son of legendary Jimmy Riley) keeps the rasta flag flying. At the same time he has such a broad vision that he can jump from original songs to covers of Michael Jackson and John Legend.  In the course of three albums, Tarrus Riley has won listeners both in Jamaica, USA and Europe with his mix of roots reggae, soul and R&amp;B. And naturally, sunny music of this caliber comes with a large, well-playing live band.  Tarrus Riley helps ensure the survival of classic reggae. " web="http://tarrusriley.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/tarrus-riley/" duration="0" title="Roots reggae from Jamaica." scene="" ros_id="113" artist="Tarrus riley &amp; the black soil band" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.516Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/tarrus-riley/id117750025?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="115" description="Good news for toughies of all genders and ages: Rob Zombie, HellBilly Deluxe, visits Roskilde Festival with one of his surprising rock rackets.  The long-haired hell man is both a musician and filmmaker, which shows in the man's extravagantly visual stage shows. Rob Zombie entertains with a horror-packed show that is perfect for the artist's industrial-influenced heavy rock.  It's classic, bad-to-the-bone rock in the tradition of Ozzy Osbourne and Alice Cooper, but with an extra morbid twist lifted from today's most depraved gore films. " web="http://www.robzombie.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/rob-zombie/" duration="0" title="Magnificent horror rock show." scene="" ros_id="114" artist="Rob zombie" artist_initial="R" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.516Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/rob-zombie/id110374?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="PAK" id="116" description="Percussive trance from one of the finest representatives of Sufi mysticism.  He has been deaf since childhood. Yet, Gonga Sain is one of Pakistan's most acclaimed percussion artists.  Together with his brother Mithu Sain he performs rituals of the spiritual world of Islamic Sufi mysticism, played on Dhol – special drums used for this kind of music since the golden age of Sufi ceremonies between the years 900 and 1400.  With an almost occult sense of rhythm and repetition, the duo creates a magical trance state, almost as otherworldly and enigmatic as the dizzying patterns of a Persian rug. " web="http://www.myspace.com/gongasainmithusain" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/gonga-sain-mithu-sain/" duration="0" title="Percussive trance from one of the finest representatives of Sufi mysticism." scene="" ros_id="115" artist="Gonga sain &amp; mithu sain" artist_initial="G" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.516Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="instrumental" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="US" id="117" description=" Marissa Paternoster – guitarist, vocalist and front woman of Screaming Females – is like a small nuclear bomb on stage. &amp;nbsp; She sings, screams and chastises herself through utterly unvarnished garage rock songs that are driven forward by equal parts ill-temper and the fundamental joy of playing a loud guitar riff.   Screaming Females seize the audience by the throat and keep a firm grip despite a spartan base consisting of guitar, bass and drums.   All fans of punk, garage and ultra-potent front women should not cheat themselves out of experiencing this trio from New Jersey.  Alle fans af punk, garage og ultrapotente frontkvinder snyder sig selv, hvis de går glip af denne trio fra New Jersey.  Released on: Don Giovanni / import" web="http://www.screamingfemales.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/screaming-females/" duration="0" title="Ultra-potent garage rock." scene="" ros_id="116" artist="Screaming females" artist_initial="S" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.517Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/screaming-females/id311088670?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="118" description="Their instrumental setup does not look like your traditional noise rock band. Selvhenter gets access to the cosmic world of sound through violin, trombone, saxophone, lots of drums and distortion pedals.  The result is a blend of noise rock, drone and jazz – a sonic breeding ground for improvisation, strange atmospheres and supernatural insights through music.  Inhale the scent of Copenhagen's most unorthodox music underground. A noisy trip into chaos with no other compass than the one provided by the music.  Released on: Eget værelse / Rillbar Distribution" web="http://www.myspace.com/selvhenterkbh" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/selvhenter/" duration="0" title="Cosmic noise jazz from the Copenhagen underground." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="117" artist="Selvhenter" artist_initial="S" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.517Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="instrumental" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="ZA" id="119" description="It is fast. The tempo typically starts at 180 beats per minute, which is faster than Western genres such as drum’n’bass.  Shangaan Electro is an only 5-year-old genre movement. In the townships of Johannesburg people from 12 to 50 are shaking their booties to this revolutionary mix of up-tempo, synthetic marimba beats and pitched vocal samples – and they can keep going for hours as long as the tempo is fast enough.  Genre mastermind Nozinja, the clown-masked Tshetsha Boys and DJ Spoko all give you the opportunity to experience a brand-new genre from first row.  Released on: Honest Jons" web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/shangaan-electro/" duration="0" title="Synthetic, African beats in high speed." scene="" ros_id="118" artist="Shangaan electro" artist_initial="S" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.518Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="african" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/album/shangaan-electro-new-wave/id378994154?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="MKD" id="120" description="Shutka Roma Rap comes from the Skopje district called Shutka – the area in Europa with the largest concentration of Romany people.  With Shutka Roma Rap, this politically vilified people have finally gotten a strong and uncompromising musical voice with the courage to add fuel to the political fires and speak up for a generation of young Romany people who once and for all want to root out racism.  We are proud to present a rap act with a message – and something at stake. " web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/shutka-roma-rap/" duration="0" title="Gangser rap with a message - and something at stake." scene="" ros_id="119" artist="Shutka roma rap" artist_initial="S" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.518Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rap" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="S" id="121" description=" Roskilde Festival has plugged in amplifiers for several of the big buffs from the Swedish metal scene: In Flames, At The Gates, Amon Amarth. So it is obvious that Soilwork now pays a visit.   The Swedish metal heroes from Helsingborg has brought the Swedish melodic metal style to a huge audience.   The Panic Broadcast, Soilwork's eighth album, is a peak from a band that after changing lineups now has just the right setup to blow back your hair with both the brutal and epic melodic songs.   Archetypal Swedish metal with red-hot racing stripes and infectious choruses.  Released on: Nuclear Blast / Warner" web="http://www.soilwork.org/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/soilwork-1/" duration="0" title="Melodic Swedish metal." scene="" ros_id="120" artist="Soilwork" artist_initial="S" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.518Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/soilwork/id6767103?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="122" description="“Have you seen my psychedelic wallpaper?” sings front man Aramis (aka Uffe Lorenzen known from Baby Woodrose and Dragontears) on Danish band Spids Nøgenhat’s already classic 2001 debut En Mærkelig Kop Te (a strange cup of tea). And the answer is yes: more and more have both seen and heard the amazing colours that this four-piece conjures up in their 60s and 70s-inspired mushroom rock. With just one album, the band has gotten an almost cult-like status among Danish music freaks.  The rare performances by Spids Nøgenhat are like psychedelic sessions that will appeal to all lovers of psychedelic rock and strange plants.  Released on: Orpheus" web="http://www.myspace.com/spidsnogenhat" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/spids-noegenhat/" duration="0" title="Psychedelic, Danish-language mushroom rock." scene="" ros_id="121" artist="Spids nøgenhat" artist_initial="S" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.518Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/id205119572?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="123" description="They are responsible for the perhaps most important rock album of the new millennium. The Strokes and the debut album Is This It? lead the way for a much welcome new wave of guitar rock in 2001.  10 years later, The Strokes extends their already superb song catalog with album number four, Angles, an album that – to a greater degree than before – contains contributions from all band members.  The photogenic lads have already changed rock history for the better. Now they stand ready to prove why we still, in 2011, need their catchy hooks, laid-back cool-cat attitude and striking choruses.  Released on: RCA / Sony Music" web="http://new.thestrokes.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/the-strokes-1/" duration="0" title="Guitar rock with strong choruses and cool NYC attitude." scene="" ros_id="122" artist="The strokes" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.518Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/the-strokes/id560289?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="124" description="Imagine The Beach Boys if they had grown up listening to the first Weezer albums. Surfer Blood could be this band.   The four-piece from Florida writes songs that seethe with a zest for life, frustration and a great love of guitar rock from the 90s. Even the most youth-heartbreaking outbursts on the successful debut Astral Coast regain the will to live when the brilliant riffs and choruses take over.   Surfer Blood's forthright attitude and winning melodies may very well establish them broadly as one of America's next big guitar rock bands. So if you are still not among the fortunate initiated: surf's up! " web="http://www.surferblood.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/surfer-blood/" duration="0" title="Charming guitar rock." scene="" ros_id="123" artist="Surfer blood" artist_initial="S" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.519Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/surfer-blood/id340033375?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="125" description=" They are indeed beautiful swans – but not the kind that pop up happily at the end of Hans Christian Andersen's fairy tale. Swans are responsible for some of New York's, perhaps the Western world's, most nihilistic music.   As part of the 80s' no wave scene, Swans experimented with noise and drone sounds for the inspiration of a whole generation of bands. On later albums Michael Gira's baritone vocals haunt a burned soundscape where black post-punk and a pronounced sense of tragic beauty form a melodic synthesis.   Now Swans have landed again – ready to explore the seemingly infinite shades of darkness existing in Michael Gira's sewer-black soul.  Released on: Young God / import" web="http://swans.pair.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/swans-1/" duration="0" title="Legendary masters of darkness from New York." scene="" ros_id="124" artist="Swans" artist_initial="S" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.519Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/swans/id5580746?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="S" id="126" description="He sounds like a protest singer who could have jammed with Bob Dylan and Joan Baez in the early 60s.  But The Tallest Man On Earth comes from Sweden and was born in the 80s. Fortunately, good music does not care about time, place and age.  Kristian Mattson's raspy voice has a resonance so that you can practically sense the American prairie under your feet.  The international press agrees regarding the album The Wild Hunt: you do not have to stand on tiptoe to see the Swede's musical references. His talent is nonetheless staggering.  The Tallest Man On Earth gets his acoustic guitar to glow and the old days to seem new again.  Released on: Gravitation/import" web="http://www.thetallestmanonearth.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/the-tallest-man-on-earth/" duration="0" title="Acoustic folk with a sound taken from the American 60s." scene="" ros_id="125" artist="The tallest man on earth" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.519Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="acoustic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/the-tallest-man-on-earth/id206564311?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="AUS" id="127" description="Their 2010 debut album Innerspeaker sounds like a forgotten masterpiece released on vinyl in the late 60s.  Tame Impala has skillfully picked up the tricks from psychedelic bands such as Cream and The Beatles – but also more contemporary mushroom pickers such as The Flaming Lips.  A mildly drugged vibe hangs over each note from the young band. It is the sound of smiling dolphins swimming through the big blue while the soft-as-cotton vocals, jazzy drums and laid-back guitar drift through the melodies like warm ripples at the edge of the lagoon.  Tame Impala takes you to a comfortable place off the map by means of jam sessions, dreamy vocal harmonies and evergreen melodies.  Released on: Modular / import" web="http://www.tameimpala.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/tame-impala/" duration="0" title="Psychedelic rock from a pink cloud." scene="" ros_id="126" artist="Tame impala" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.519Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/tame-impala/id290242959?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="128" description="Keep seaching if you are looking for reinventions of the wheel. Terror prefer to do a show where the good old wheel turns at roaring and shattering speed with a discharge of muscular but melodic hardcore.  Keepers of the Faith from 2010 convinces of one of Terror’s main objectives: a fuming crowd full of sweaty girls and boys.  Terror embodies the hardcore lifestyle with a flicked finger to about 95 % of the surrounding world. Shake those tattoos to a round of pure back-to-basics hardcore.  Released on: Century Media / EMI" web="http://www.myspace.com/terror" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/terror/" duration="0" title="Hardcore true to its roots." scene="" ros_id="127" artist="Terror" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.519Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/terror/id19123484?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="S" id="129" description="The dark mechanical beats are thriving.  This Is Head is inspired by bands such as New Order, The Cure and Neu! with a sense of dedication and seriousness alien to many trendy hit makers.  Most songs are instrumental and all tracks have a number for a title. Still, Henric, Adam, Tom and Björn are able to create catchy tunes from their mechanical and experimental pop. This Malmö band has just won the ”pop of the year” award from Swedish National Radio.  Released on: Adrian / Sony Music" web="http://thisishead.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/this-is-head/" duration="0" title="Mechanical pop with room enough for both experiments and catchy tunes" scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="128" artist="This is head" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.520Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="130" description="Avant-garde approaches to songwriting is not a new thing for mastermind Nis Bysted. With Thulebasen he shows how an experimental and raving approach to music can also be used in a more straightforwardly rocking, song-oriented universe.  The album Gate 5 from 2011 sounds unlike anything we have heard from a Danish band.  Thulebasen is expanded with Felia and Niels-Kristian, and together the three let &amp;nbsp;improvisation and playfulness take control. Be guided into a parallel world of warped avant-garde, rattling guitar dissonance in the vein of Sonic Youth and surprisingly catchy elements.  Released on: Tambourhinoceros / Playground" web="http://www.thulebasen.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/thulebasen/" duration="0" title="Clattering future rock brewed on intuition and playfulness." scene="" ros_id="129" artist="Thulebasen" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.520Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/thulebasen/id411161953?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="S" id="131" description="Timbuktu once again brings his playmates in Damn! on tour, and with their expertise in Afro funk, reggae, Latin and Swedish folk music you are up for a different hip hop treat.   With a live energy that can take the breath away from every marathon runner, it is no wonder that Timbuktu over the past many years has been at the very top of Nordic hip hop. A position that can only be maintained because he is never afraid to put himself at the front line with political songs, self-revealing lyrics, musical detours and a wry smile that reaches the back rows.  Released on: Ju Ju / EMI" web="http://www.timbuk.nu/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/timbuktu-damn-2/" duration="0" title="Crème de la crème of Nordic hip hop." scene="" ros_id="130" artist="Timbuktu &amp; damn!" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.520Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="hippo" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/timbuktu/id415059986?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="N" id="132" description="One of Norway's new pop comets is called Tôg. The seven-piece is inspired by new wave, Italian disco and, according to themselves, various horror and western flicks.  Their song &quot;Sansen&quot; was one of last summer's big hits up north, and musical Norway licks its lips in anticipation of the debut album in May from the Stavanger band.  Tôg means fool in the local dialect, which is also the language of the songs. However, front figure Lars Christian Olsen seems to have the upper hand with his danceable, organ-adorned pop music.  Released on: Brilliance / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/togstavanger" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/tog/" duration="0" title="Pop comets with a Stavanger dialect." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="131" artist="Tog" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.520Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="pop" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="ARG" id="133" description="South American music is put in a futuristic acid bath with Tremor.   The trio has Leo Martinelli in front, composer, musical archaeologist and performing musician. His starting point is the traditional instruments from Argentina – especially the upright bombo legüero, a bass drum that is a characteristic part of Tremor's stage show.   The traditional Argentinean sounds are part of a musical pairing with contemporary electronica and synthesizers. In this way Tremor creates a sound space with fascinating contrasts between past, present and future.  Released on: ZZK Records / import" web="http://www.tremormusic.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/tremor/" duration="0" title="South America 2.0." scene="" ros_id="132" artist="Tremor" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.520Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/tremor/id27171630?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="134" description="There are only two men onstage. Yet, Trust kick in the interplanetary door to distant galaxies when they play progressive rock in true garage style.  Here you will find Ozzy-esque vocals, stony riffs, cleverly dribbling drumming and tackling rhythm changes. It sounds exhausting and complex but is rather hot, energetic and fundamental.  Guitar hard rock with a penchant for occult sci-fi and music from the 70s.  Released on: Play/Rec" web="http://www.myspace.com/abandcalledtrust" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/trust-1/" duration="0" title="Planetary guitar hard rock." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="133" artist="Trust" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.520Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/trust/id4677691?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="135" description="The Brooklyn band TV On The Radio mixes rock and post-punk with electronica and soul. The musical range and the solid songs have earned the band a position as absolute heavyweights of indie rock just as they are no strangers on best-of-the-year lists.  TV On The Radio have recently released their fourth album, Nine Types of Light, once again followed by – the almost usual – praise and critical acclaim.  The success was unfortunately followed by news that the band's bassist Gerard Smith had passed away. Fortunately, they are a band keen to play themselves out of the mourning. Look forward to them doing so at Roskilde Festival 2011.  Released on: Interscope / Universal" web="http://www.tvontheradio.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/tv-on-the-radio-1/" duration="0" title="Indie rulers visit Roskilde with success and sorrow under their belt." scene="" ros_id="134" artist="Tv on the radio" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.521Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/tv-on-the-radio/id6562624?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="136" description="Copenhagen has a stinky, rotten-as-a-corpse metal band that more fans of metal, cruelty and brutality deserve to know.  On the debut album Indhentet af døden (run down by death) Undergang delivers heavy-as-anvil, old-school death metal. The bass is tuned down so much that it is often felt more than heard, the vocalist's growls are so deep that he most of all sounds like a glacial storm on its way across the mainland.  Undergang will melt your face with a number of coal-black hymns about death, our cloaked ruler.  Released on: Xtreem Music / Target" web="http://www.myspace.com/undergang666" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/undergang/" duration="0" title="Death metal from the old school." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="135" artist="Undergang" artist_initial="U" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.521Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="US" id="137" description=" In America's huge array of rough but melodic metalcore bands, Underøath has always stood as one of the most refreshing groups.   On Ø (Disambiguation) from 2010 you sense a band reconsidering its sound. The pop choruses are gone. Instead the album has the same organic expression that you experience live. Wild, crushing and punishing.   None of the original members are in the band any longer. Yet, this new incarnation delivers a round of flame-enshrouded metal about chaos, drug problems and the Lord.  Released on: Roadrunner / Warner" web="http://www.underoath777.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/underoeath/" duration="0" title="Chaotic metalcore." scene="" ros_id="136" artist="Underøath" artist_initial="U" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.521Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="metal" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/underoath/id1750355?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="COL" id="138" description="In the home country they call him &quot;El Mago&quot; (the wizard). You learn why once you let go the reins to these sputtering and cheerful tones.  Anibal Velasquez has since 1952 made ​​over 300 albums. The accordion player has conquered his homeland Colombia – and great parts of the rest of South America –with his blend of Caribbean styles such as salsa, mambo, cumbia and his own version of Cuban guaracha.  All the songs you will hear from this legendary trendsetter are packed with musical history, hot percussion and some of the most superb accordion playing you can imagine.  Released on: Analog Africa / import" web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/anibal-velasquez-y-su-conjunto/" duration="0" title="Masterly accordion player and trendsetter." scene="" ros_id="137" artist="Anibal velasquez y los locos del swing " artist_initial="A" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.524Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="instrumental" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="139" description="Dark tones have always characterised Veto.  As one of the most critically acclaimed and audience-appreciated bands, the sombre style may seem paradoxical – but front man Troels Abrahamsen has never let the steadily growing success block his artistic vision.  The starting point is British, alternative rock, but the four Danes add a more distinct electronic touch to the music that is constantly sprawling, ticking and hissing inside the dark soundscapes.  With three rainy electro rock albums under the belt, Veto has really established itself on the Danish rock scene.  Released on: RCA / Sony Music" web="http://www.vetonet.dk/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/veto-2/" duration="0" title="Danish champions in dark electronic rock." scene="" ros_id="138" artist="Veto" artist_initial="V" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.524Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/veto/id31385629?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="140" description="The American highway is quite easily interpreted from the privacy of your bedroom. On Kurt Vile’s homemade records you can hear classic American radio rock rummaging behind the finger picked guitar and the reverb enveloped vocals that can grow from a snuffling to a shout in no time.  Yet these slightly simple arrangements leave the impression of an experimenting soul. An hunger for creation that almost wants to take a bite of you. Kurt Vile’s music combines the scent of cactus and dusty highways with a homemade skewed feeling that encompasses American indie rock.&amp;nbsp;  Backing band The Violators are the young American’s faithful companions when this lively alternative highway rock transcends the home studio to the rock stage.&amp;nbsp;  Released on: Matador / Playground" web="http://www.kurtvile.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/kurt-vile-the-violators/" duration="0" title="Highway rock from the bedroom." scene="" ros_id="139" artist="Kurt vile &amp; the violators" artist_initial="K" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.524Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/kurt-vile/id274234314?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="US" id="141" description="Desperate but always hopeful The Walkmen have, in the course of many albums, become experts at portraying the human condition in classic rock songs.  Several members even have a history with the noir-rock band Jonathan Fire*Eater who played at Roskilde Festival in 1997.&amp;nbsp; Electric guitars, electric organ and a hardworking drummer are all key elements in The Walkmen’s nostalgic sound.  However, lead singer Hamilton Leithauser’s soul-wrenching croon is the band's primary instrument. With this weather-beaten voice in front, every song from the band is a show of quiet desperation and clattering charm.  Released on: Bella Union / Cosmos Music Group" web="http://thewalkmenmusic.blogspot.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/the-walkmen/" duration="0" title="Rustic, crushing guitar rock." scene="" ros_id="140" artist="The walkmen" artist_initial="T" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.524Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/the-walkmen/id5305611?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="CHN" id="142" description="Silence is the mother of all music. It is also the starting point for Wang Li in his absolutely minimal compositions on the Chinese Jew's harp, a popular instrument already 500 years BC.  The Chinese musician has been at both a monastic seminary and at an academy of music in France. Furthermore, he has traveled and played contemporary music in his homeland.  Wang Li brings both spiritual insight and a broad cultural frame of reference with him as he explores silence with his ​​delicate mouth instrument.  Released on: Buda Musique / import" web="" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/wang-li/" duration="0" title="Transcendental meditations on Jew's harp." scene="" ros_id="141" artist="Wang li" artist_initial="W" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.524Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="US" id="143" description="This is the sound of black hearts in white noise. Weekend is for everyone who likes noise rock and post-punk, especially from the 80s.  The young band makes a virtue of lowering our ears into sonic dissonance: brutal guitar feedback and towering decibel levels that could force even Godzilla on his knees.  The tracks on the debut album Sports do not use cheap tricks but respect the legacy of bands such as Joy Division, The Jesus and Mary Chain and My Bloody Valentine – lo-fi, punk aesthetics and noise in an uncompromising union.  Look forward to a visit from one of the coolest and most promising noise rock bands from the US west coast.   Released on: Slumberland / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/weekendmusic" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/weekend/" duration="0" title="Brand-new noise rock for seasoned ears." scene="" ros_id="142" artist="Weekend" artist_initial="W" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.525Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/weekend/id110476918?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="ISL" id="144" description="Icelandic bands can also make the ground shake. Just listen to Who Knew’s semi-desperate, hot guitar rock.  The expression is hard-hitting, strangely uplifting and performed with the same devil-may-care apathy as with bands such as Modest Mouse and Wolf Parade.  A summer soundtrack for anyone with a penchant for moody atmospheres, falsetto vocals in harmony and rich amounts of melodious guitars and keyboards.  Released on: DevilDuck / import" web="http://www.myspace.com/wellwhoknew" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/who-knew/" duration="0" title="Manic-depressive indie rock full of energy." scene="Pavilion Junior" ros_id="143" artist="Who knew" artist_initial="W" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.525Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/who-knew/id272402775?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="DK" id="145" description="The mirror ball and the electric guitar are good friends. Just ask WhoMadeWho. The Danes are loved far and wide (Josh Homme himself has played a cover version of &quot;Space for Rent&quot;) for their mutated, hand-played disco rock.  And the trio's diverse backgrounds in jazz, electronica and alternative rock never denies itself. The style is humorous, the mood is cheerful and WhoMadeWho can win over the audience whether they appear in semi-bizarre one-piece suits or just walk onstage in their own civilian clothes.  Released on: Kompakt / A:larm" web="http://www.whomadewho.dk/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/whomadewho-1/" duration="0" title="Dance-friendly rock for a turning mirror ball." scene="" ros_id="144" artist="Whomadewho" artist_initial="W" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.525Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="rock" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/whomadewho/id332944048?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="FR" id="146" description="French-language pop music is to many a special combination of innocence and eroticism.  This is also the case of Yelle who, dressed in showy costumes, continues the French tradition of semi-suggestive elegance in a different, feminist way.  Never mind if you do not understand a word of her songs. You are still elevated by the pop hooks and the danceable sway of the music that is also captured on two albums, latest Safari Disco Club.  Yelle is a French branch of the same musical family as Goldfrapp and Robyn.  Released on: Recreation Center / Cosmos Music Group" web="http://www.yelle.fr/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/yelle/" duration="0" title="Electronic, French-language pop." scene="" ros_id="145" artist="Yelle" artist_initial="Y" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.525Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="electronic" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/yelle/id160360801?uo=4"/>
	<Concert country="ISR" id="147" description="Ravid Kahalani is Israeli with a Yemeni background and rigorous studies of the Torah behind him, but he has for many years absorbed in genres such as jazz-blues, delta blues and desert blues.  With Yemen Blues, Kahalani returns to his roots that are nourished by the many musical impressions and now sprout in completely unexpected ways.  Yemen Blues blends the ancient sound of the (un)happy Arabia with brass, cross flute and percussion. He brings everything together in a fragrant potpourri full of blues and jazzy finesse.  The result is both festive, musical and universal: a proof of the common humanity hiding behind all forms of blues.  Released on: LGM / import" web="http://www.yemenblues.com/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/yemen-blues/" duration="0" title="Jazz-blues with a Middle Eastern spice." scene="" ros_id="146" artist="Yemen blues" artist_initial="Y" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.525Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="jazz" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="NL" id="148" description="Behind the name Zea hides Dutch multi-instrumentalist and singer Arnold de Boer who with his frantic one-man project delivers highly energetic electro punk and schizophrenic indie pop.  Zea has released four albums and toured intensively throughout the world – including an extensive tour in Ethiopia. On stage he is reputed to giving it full throttle, and both singing, playing guitar and dancing maniacally around while simultaneously keeping track of an arsenal of drum machines and synthesizers.  The music has been described as an obscure mix between They Might Be Giants, Ramones and a punk version of Pink Floyd.  Besides being busy with Zea, Arnold de Boer has since 2009 been the lead singer of legendary Dutch punk band The Ex.  The act plays as part of the The Ex curation on the Pavilion stage.  Released on: Makkum / import" web="http://www.zea.dds.nl/" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/zea/" duration="0" title="Forceful one-man army." scene="" ros_id="147" artist="Zea" artist_initial="Z" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.525Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="instrumental" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes=""/>
	<Concert country="INT" id="149" description="Bristol four-piece Zun Zun Egui is principally considered a British band – but this is really a rainbow-coloured explosion of nationalities, genres and musical languages.  Lead singer Kushal Gaya babbles and coos in an often unrecognizable Esperanto. The other band members also evoke associations from parts all over the world. African guitar, Japanese avant-garde and jazzy post-rock from Chicago clash in a Dadaist carnival – a sound nightmare for everyone who demands clear-cut genre borders. Fans of Frank Zappa, Mike Patton and Talking Heads will nod appreciatively.&amp;nbsp;" web="http://www.myspace.com/zunzunegui" link="http://roskilde-festival.dk/uk/bands/singleband/zun-zun-egui/" duration="0" title="Pleasant frenzy music with a global colour." scene="" ros_id="148" artist="Zun zun egui" artist_initial="Z" updated_timestamp="2011-06-02T09:04:01.526Z" begin_timestamp="" end_timestamp="0" genre="alternate" thumb_url="" image_url="" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/dk/artist/zun-zun-egui/id337216935?uo=4"/>
</concerts>
